#Brazil#
# Where hearts
were entertained in June #
# We stood beneath
an amber moon #
#And softly murmured
someday soon #
- #Someday #
- # We'd kiss #
# We'd kiss ##
# Central Services #
# We do the work
You do the pleasure ##
Hi there.
I want to talk to you about ducts.
Do your ducts seem old-fashioned,
out-of-date?
Central Services's new duct designs...
are now available
in hundreds of different colors...
to suit your individual taste.
Hurry now, while stocks last,
to your nearest Central Services showroom.
Designer colors to suit
your demanding taste.
Tonight we have with us,
from the Ministry of Information...
Deputy Minister Eugene Helpmann.
Good evening, David.
What do you believe is behind
this recent increase in terrorist bombings?
Bad sportsmanship.
A ruthless minority of people...
seems to have forgotten certain
good old-fashioned virtues.
They just can't stand
seeing the other fella win.
If these people
would just play the game...
they'd get a lot more out of life.
Nevertheless, Mr. Helpmann,
there are those who maintain...
that the Ministry of Information
has become too large and unwieldy.
David, in a free society,
information's the name of the game.
You can't win the game
if you're a man short.
And the cost of it all, Deputy Minister.
Seven percent of the gross national product.
I understand this concern
on behalf of the taxpayer.
People want value for money.
That's why we always insist on the principle
of information retrieval charges.
It's absolutely right and fair...
that those found guilty should pay
for their periods of detention...
and for the information retrieval
procedures used in their interrogation.
Do you believe that the government
is winning the battle against terrorists?
Oh, yes. Our morale
is much higher than theirs.
We're fielding all their strokes,
running a lot of them out...
and pretty consistently
knocking them for six.
I'd say they're nearly out of the game.
... law-abiding citizens
to have to subsidize criminals?
But, Mr. Helpmann, the bombing campaign
is now in its 13th year.
Beginner's luck.
Thank you very much,
Deputy Minister.
Thank you, David.
And a very merry Christmas
to you all.
"Scrooge was better than his word.
"He did it all, and infinitely more.
"And to Tiny Tim, who did not die...
"he became a second father.
"He became as good a friend
in the good old worid.
"And so, as Tiny Tim observed...
God bless us, every one."
- Are you boys giving me the runaround?
- Where are you?
Step right up. This way. Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Don't throw that.
That's only for long distance.
All right.
- I'm sorry, boys, but we haven't got any vacancies.
- Got no vacancies.
- We got plenty of rooms.
- That's all right. We take a room.
- All right.
- All right. We take a vacancy.
Boy, take the gentlemen's baggage.
Who's there?
Who is that?
Father Christmas can't come
if we haven't got a chimney.
You'll see.
No!
What's going on?
I hereby inform you,
under powers entrusted to me...
under section 47, paragraph 7
of council order number 438476...
That Mr. Buttle, Archibald, residing at
412 North Tower, Shangrila Towers...
has been invited to assist the Ministry
of Information with certain inquiries...
and that he is liable to
certain financial obligations...
as specified in council order
RB/CZ/907/X.
Sign here, please.
Where are you taking him?
There.
Thank you.
Same again, please.
Just there.
Press harder his time.
- Good.
- What is this all about?
That is your receipt for your husband.
Thank you.
And this is my receipt for your receipt.
Mrs. Buttle, are you okay?
- Ho! Ho!
- We're Department of Works!
Department of Works up here.!
Careful with those bloody things.
Don't take any notice of them, love.
Don't touch me.
Why don't you just get the hell out of here.
Don't you worry, love.
We'll have everything shipshape in a jiffy.
- That's it. Nothing to worry about.
- Right. It's Tuttle downstairs who can worry, eh?
Tuttle? His name's Buttle.
There must be some mistake.
Mistake?
We don't make mistakes.
That's bloody typical.
They've gone back to metric
without telling us.
Mrs. Buttle, are you all right?
Yeah.
"Buttle."
Buttle, Archibald.
Ridiculous name.
On the twenty...
Oh, shit.
Mr...
Mr. Lowry, would you
step in here, please?
Ah.
I say, h-has anybody seen Lowry?
Has anybody seen Sam Lowry?
Sam.
- Hello.
- Hello? Sam. Where are you?
- Hello?
- It's 11:00.
- What?
- 11:00!
- Mr. Kurtzmann.
- Yes.
You're up late.
- It's 11:00.
- Is it?
Oh. The electrics here are up the spout.
- I know. Look...
- Oh, yours too?
- Yes.
- Oh, well, um, I'll be there as soon as I can.
- Yes. Thanks. Bye.
- Hurry up.
Hello, Sammy.
What have you got to say?
Oh, very good, Sammy.
... famous statue
pairing truth and freedom.
This is not the only statue...
Shut up!
What's this gun for?
This one, Sister,
is a nine-millimeter submachine gun...
used for close-quarter combat fighting.
Very effective weapon.
Would you like to see it?
Sam!
Jack!
- Well...
- Long time no see.
- Hey.
- What are you doing here?
I don't expect to see you
slumming it in Records.
- What's the problem?
- Problem? No problem.
Everything's fine. Wonderful. Marvelous.
Alison's in great shape.
Kids are fine.
I'm on Security Level 5 now,
so Mr. Helpmann relies on me more and more.
- It's been a great year.
- You sound worried.
Worried? Me?
If I'm worried about anyone, Sam, it's you.
I mean, look at you, Sam.
Whatever happened to you?
Records?
Sam, you were one of the brightest...
Sam?
Uh, Jack, it's great to see you.
- I'm gonna be late.
- Sam.
Let a friend tell you.
Your life is going wrong.
Records is a dead-end department.
No security level worth a damn.
- It's impossible to get noticed.
- I know.
Wonderful. Marvelous.
Perfect. See you, Jack.
- Give my regards to Alison and the twins.
- Triplets.
Triplets? God.
How time flies.
A very clear delineation of picture this has.
Adamant, mobile.
Next.
I want to report a wrongful arrest.
You want Information Adjustments.
Different department.
I've been to Information Adjustments.
They sent me here. They said
you have a form I need to fill out.
Have you got an arrest receipt?
Yeah.
- Is it stamped?
- Stamped?
No, no.
There's no stamp on it, you see.
I can't let you have the form
until this is stamped.
- Where do I get it stamped?
- Information Adjustments.
It's nothing. It's nothing.
It keeps picking up old films.
That can't be right, can it?
Perhaps the machine's on the blink.
No, it's not the machine. There's a mismatch
on the personnel code numbers.
Tuttle should have had £31.06 debited
against his account, not Buttle.
- My God! A mistake!
- Well, at least it's not ours.
Isn't it? Whose is it?
- Information Retrieval.
- Oh, good.
Yeah. See, Expediting has put in
for electrical procedures...
in respect of Buttle, Archibald,
shoe repair operative...
but Security has invoiced Admin
for Tuttle, Archibald, heating engineer.
Oh, what a relief.
Finish your tea, Sam.
What? Oh. Thanks.
I don't know what I would do
if you ever got promoted.
- Oh, God, don't worry about that.
- No, but if they did promote you, uh...
I've told you before.
I'd turn it down.
- Would you? Really?
- Really.
You've been promoted.
It's your mother, isn't it?
Pulling strings again.
Sam, it's time for you
to grow up and accept responsibility.
Your poor father would be appalled
at your lack of promotion. Ooh!
Mother, I just wish
you would stop interfering.
I don't want promotion.
I'm happy where I am.
No, you're not.
Jack Lint is a lesson to you.
He doesn't have your brains,
but he's got the ambition.
You haven't got the ambition.
Luckily, you've got me
and the deputy minister.
- Mr. Helpmann was very close to your father.
- Now, please, Mrs. Lowry.
Don't get upset.
Mr. Lowry, please wait in reception.
You're giving her wrinkles.
- You see?
- God!
Just try and relax, Mrs. Lowry.
I'll make you 20 years younger.
- Ha!
- Yoo-hoo, Dr. Jaffe. You are a genius.
Would you like to be surgeon general?
I know simply everybody.
Well, they won't know you
when I've finished with you.
First...
we remove the excess derma.
So.
Now the flaccid tissues
under the eyes and the forehead.
- Zip.
- Oh.
Now, I lift...
the wrinkles and the worry lines...
right up into the wig,
into the hairline.
Now the template.
- Mercy.
- There. Now a bit of sticky.
Like so.
And already she's twice as beautiful
as she was before. Voilà!
Mr. Helpmann was very close
to your poor father.
He was very close to me.
Still is.
He'll take you under his wing
when you get to Information Retrieval.
- Thank you, sir.
- You'll like it there.
You're not listening to me, Mother.
What the hell is this, lady?
It's a present for my son. Really!
I hope you like it.
It's very exclusive.
What on earth is it?
Something for an executive.
Ah, Madame Lowry.
You look exquisite today.
Merry Christmas.
Hello, Spiro. Merry Christmas.
- Sorry.
- Uh, you remember my son, Samuel.
- Of course.
- We're joining Mrs. Terrain.
- Yes. The lady's waiting.
- Are we? God.
This way.
Mother. Mother, I thought we were
going to be able to talk.
- We will. We will.
- Ida, Sam.
- Oh, God. She's got what's her name with her.
- Yoo-hoo.!
Sam!
Well, Alma. How are you?
You look wonderful.
Hello, Shirley.
Thank you, Spiro.
- Salt?
- Not yet.
Sam, happy Christmas.
- So sorry we're late.
- Thanks.
Now, Alma...
what are you going to have?
I can't make up my mind whether
to have the number one or the number two.
- What do you recommend, Spiro?
- Between you and me, madame...
today the number two.
Thank you, Spiro.
Shirley. Shirley, what are you going to have?
Between you and me, mademoiselle,
today the number one.
- Madame Lowry?
- Oh, to hell with the diet.
I'm going to have a number eight, please.
- A most perceptive choice if I dare say so, madame.
- Oh, Ida!
- Monsieur.
- Steak, please. Rare. Mother...
- Monsieur, quel numéro?
- I don't know which number. Mother, please...
- That one. There.
- That's fine. Thanks.
- Mother, will you please listen to me.
- Alma! You wicked girl.
- You've started your treatment.
- Say the number, please.
- You noticed.
- You have to say the number!
- Will you please go away! I'm trying to talk...
- I must tell you all about it.
Number three.
Mother, will you listen to me.
I haven't...
Numéro huit.
Braised veal in wine sauce.
It's too exciting.
I've left Dr. Jaffe and gone to Dr. Chapman.
- Numéro deux. Duck à I'orange.
- Dr. Chapman? Chapman?
Excusez-moi.
The acid man?
Really, Ida! Just because
his techniques are revolutionary...
I don't go around
calling Dr. Jaffe the knife man.
Numéro un, crevettes à la mayonnaise.
- I am sorry, Alma. I didn't mean to sound so...
- It's all right, Ida. It's just...
Steak. Numéro trois.
Mesdames, monsieur...
bon appétit.
- Merci.
Acid, on the other hand, can be used
for such wonderfully subtle shading.
Such delicate nuances.
Like a Rembrandt etching.
- And it is so much quicker.
- God!
If it wasn't for this complication... the doctor says
it could have happened to anybody...
I'd have had this dressing off yesterday.
Shirley.
Salt?
What were we saying?
- This isn't rare.
- Oh! By the by, Alma...
I saw the most wonderful idea
for Christmas presents at the chemist's.
Gift tokens. Medical gift tokens.
Oh, that sounds marvelous!
It's good at any doctor's
and most of the major hospitals.
It's also accepted
for gynecological examinations...
including cesarean section.
- Spiro.
- I'm sorry, madame. I don't know what to say.
It never really happens to us.
I'm going to do something
about it straightaway.
Really, Sam! Why can't you
do something about these terrorists?
It's my lunch hour.
Besides, it's not my department.
Actually, Alma, that was one of
the little things I've been dying to tell you.
Look. Sam's been promoted
to Information Retrieval.
Oh, that's wonderful!
Congratulations, Sam!
Stop it! I'm not being promoted.
I'm not going to Information Retrieval.
If I want you to stick your oar in, Mother,
I'll tell you where to stick it.
Pepper?
I've gotta go.
- Sam, you haven't had your dessert.
- I don't want dessert.
- I don't want promotion. I don't want anything.
- Of course you want something.
You must have hopes, wishes, dreams!
No, nothing. Not even dreams.
Sam.
Sam!
Oh, God.
Hello. Central Services?
I'm at 579B, Block 19,
Northwestern Section "D."
That's exit one on Green Pastures Highway
at the Orange Blossom Flyover.
And I've got trouble with my air-conditioning.
It's an emergency.
Thank you for calling Central Services.
I'm sorry.
Due to temporary staff shortage...
Central Services cannot take service calls
centrally between 2300 and 0900 hours.
- Have a nice day. This has not been a recording.
- This is an emergency.
Thank you for calling Central Services.
I'm sorry. Due to...
- No. I've got to have a heating engineer.
- Thank you for calling Central Services.
Oh, shit.
Hello.
- Hello.
Hello. Mr. Lowry.
Yes. Who is this?
Put the phone down
and raise your hands.
What? Who is this?
Nice and easy now.
Nice and easy.
Just keep your hands
where I can see them.
What... What are you doing?
Harry Tuttle.
Heating engineer at your service.
Tuttle?
Are you from Central Services?
I called Central Services.
Well, they're a little
overworked these days.
Luckily I intercepted your call.
You did...
Just a minute.
What was that business with the gun?
It's just a precaution, sir.
Just a precaution.
I've had traps set for me before now.
And there are plenty of people
in Central Services...
who'd love to
get their hands on Harry Tuttle.
Are you telling me that this is illegal?
Well, yes and no. Officially, only Central Service
operatives are supposed to touch this stuff.
- Would you hold this, please?
- Uh...
But nowadays,
with all the new rules and regulations...
they can't get decent staff anymore.
So they tend to turn a blind eye
as long as I'm careful.
Mind you, if ever they could prove
that I've been working on their equipment...
well, that's a pipe of a different color.
- Wouldn't it be simpler just to work...
- Would you hold this for me?
Sorry. Yes. I was saying, wouldn't it be simpler
to work with Central Services?
Nah! Nah. Couldn't stand the pa...
We're getting warm.
- You couldn't what? Couldn't stand the what?
- Paperwork. Couldn't stand the paperwork.
Listen. This whole system of yours
could be on fire...
and I couldn't even turn on a kitchen tap
without filling out a 27 B/6.
Bloody paperwork.
I suppose one has to
expect a certain amount.
Why? I came into this game
for the action, the excitement.
Go anywhere, travel light, get in, get out,
wherever there's trouble, a man alone.
Now they got the whole country sectioned off.
You can't make a move without a form.
Found it.
There's your problem.
- Can you fix it?
- No, I can't.
But I can bypass it
with one of these.
Fine by me.
- Are you expecting anyone?
- No.
- Get down!
- Wait! Wait! Will you wait!
Shh.
The flashlight.
Central Services.
- Central Services.
- Oh, yes.
- You rang, sir?
- Trouble with your air-conditioning?
- Air-conditioning, sir?
No, it's... it's... it's, uh, all right.
It's, um... It's fixed.
- Fixed.
- Fixed?
Yes, um...
I mean, it, um, fixed itself.
- Oh, it fixed itself!
- Fixed itself?
Yes!
Machines don't fix themselves.
No, they don't fix themselves, sir.
- He's tampered with it, Dowser.
- I think he's tampered with it, Mr. Spoor.
Sorry you've had a wasted journey.
Oh, that's all right.
- I think we'll go have a little look.
- No, you can't.
I think we should.
Yes, Mr. Spoor.
Have you got a 27 B/6?
27 B/6?
27...
Now look what you've done to him!
Well, have you got a 27 B/6?
Not... as such.
But we'll get one.
- It's all right. It's all right. It's all right.
- It's all right, then?
Sorry. I'm a bit of a stickler
for paperwork, you see.
I mean, where would we be
if we didn't stick to the correct procedures?
We'll be back.
We'll be back!
It's all right.
Thanks for coming.
We'll be back,
you bloody little bastard!
- Thank you.
- We'll show you.!
Well...
Thanks, Lowry.
You're a good man in a tight corner.
Thanks.
Listen, um... I, uh...
Well, I...
I just happen to work
at the Ministry of Information.
- What?
- And, uh...
Well, I just happen to know
that Information Retrieval...
are looking for an Archibald Tuttle,
heating engineer.
You, uh...
You wouldn't, by any chance...
Would you?
My good friends call me Harry.
Information Retrieval, huh?
The big boys.
What do they want you for?
- Time to go.
- Sorry.
How's that?
Listen, you, um... you really must
let me give you something.
How much will it be for the, uh...
for the work?
Ah, come on.
You did me a favor.
Just check the corridor.
Oh. Well, thanks.
Listen, kid,
we're all in it together.
- Go on.
- Right.
Okay.
All clear.
I think Kurtzmann
is getting suspicious.
What's playing today?
Casablanca.
Mr. Lowry, will you step in here, please.
Lowry.!
Sam Lowry.!
Psst!
Thank God you're here.
We're in terrible trouble.
Shh.
- Look at this. Look at this.
- It's a check.
It's the refund for Tuttle.
- Tuttle?
- Mm-hmm.
No, no. Buttle.
I mean Buttle.
It's been confusion
from the word go.
He's been overcharged for
Information Retrieval procedures...
and someone somewhere
is trying to make us carry the can.
Can I have a look?
I've never seen a refund check before.
I'll bet it's Jeffries.
Yes.
He always believes that people should
pay more for their interrogation.
And "B," he loathes me.
We've gotta get rid of it!
Well, send it to somebody else.
Better still, send it to Buttle.
After all, it's his check.
I've tried that.
But look. Look at this.
You see? The population census
has gotten him down as "dormanted."
Uh, the Central Collective Storehouse computer
has got him down as "deleted."
Hang on.
Information Retrieval
has got him down as "inoperative."
Security has got him down as "excised."
- Administration has him down as "completed."
- He's dead.
Le...
Dead?
Well, that's awful.
We'll never get rid
of the damn thing now.
What we gonna do, Sam?
Could try next of kin.
Next of kin!
Yes!
There we go.
Buttle. Veronica. Mrs.
Veronica?
What's the number on the check?
Uh, 27156789...
/074328K.
Right. Into memory.
Central Banking.
Veronica Buttle.
Mrs.
Deposit.
Thank God for that.
Uh, would you like some tea?
There's a problem.
She doesn't have a bank account.
Well, that's it, then.
I might just as well
go and hang myself now.
This sort of thing could never have happened
before this stupid seventh-tier reorganization.
That's Simmons's doing. And he and Jeffries
always sit together at lunch.
Bastards!
Sh... Shh. Shh.
Perhaps we could lose the thing behind
a filing cabinet or something... burn it, eat it.
Look, there is one solution.
What?
Drive out to Mrs. Buttle,
let her sign the back of the check.
She can cash it
at the corner sweet shop.
That's brilliant, Sam.
I'll even do it for you.
Here, authorize the check.
What's the address?
Everything's in here.
Uh, w-what should I do next?
Pink and blue receipts.
Sign there, there and there.
- And sign the check there.
- Yes.
I think I've broken a bone.
Look, my wrist is all limp.
What a pathetic creature I am!
Here.
I'll do it for you.
Right.
I'll be on my way.
Sam?
You are good to me, you know.
- Here's looking at you, kid.
- Here's looking at you.
#Brazil #
# Where hearts
were entertained in June #
# We stood beneath an amber moon #
We interrupt this program to bring you news
of a terrorist bombing at the Blue Lagoon...
#And clung together #
# Then #
# Tomorrow was another day #
# The morning found me miles away #
# With still a million things to say #
#Now #
# When twilight dims the sky above #
#Recalling ##
Under Section 972/552.
Hello. I wonder
if you could tell me where the...
Piss off!
Hello.
I'll never confess!
Hey, come on!
You gotta interrogate me!
Mrs. Buttle?
Uh, Mrs. Buttle?
Ah. Um, are you Mrs. Buttle?
Um...
my name's Lowry.
Uh, Sam Lowry.
Um, I'm from
the Ministry of Information.
I've come to give you a check.
Um, it's a refund, actually.
- There was a mistake.
- Mistake?
Yes, yes.
Not in my department, of course.
I'm only Records.
No, it, uh...
I'll tell you what it is.
It seems that Mr. Buttle was overcharged
by Information Retrieval.
Yes, they don't usually make mistakes,
but, uh...
well, I suppose we're all human.
Oh!
What happened to the, um...
Actually, you know, my coming here
is rather unorthodox, bringing you this check...
as any payments are normally
made through Central Computer, but, um...
Well, as there were
certain... difficulties...
we thought,
well, rather than cause delay...
we'd let you have it now.
You know, it being Christmas and all.
My husband's dead, isn't he?
Um, I do assure you, Mrs. Buttle,
the ministry is very scrupulous...
about following up
and eradicating any error.
But if you do have any complaints
you wish to make...
I'd be, well, only too happy
to send you the appropriate forms.
What have you done with his body?
Oh!
Gosh.
Um, I-I don't know
anything about that, Mrs. Buttle.
I'm really just delivering the check.
So, if, um... Look, if you wouldn't mind
just signing these two receipts...
I'd be only too happy to, uh...
to leave you in peace.
He hadn't done anything.
He was good!
What have you done
with his body?
It isn't being very helpful, Mrs. Buttle.
I didn't have to come here,
you know, Mrs. Buttle.
I'll kill you!
I'll kill you, you bastard!
Hey!
Get off!
Are you all right?
Mrs. Buttle, are you all right?
It's you!
Wait! Stop! Don't go! Stop!
Oh, look.! He'll never get that out.!
Stop! I had nothing
to do with it! Wait!
Stop!
He's coming back.!
Jesus Christ!
Jesus...
- Go away.
- Her name's Jill.
What? Jill?
Jill who? Jill who?
Layton.
Jill Layton.
You're a very good little girl.
What are you doing here?
Waiting for my daddy.
He will be pleased
when he gets home.
Sam, I've just
had the Transport Pool onto me.
You don't anything about a personnel transporter
gone missing, do you?
Personnel transporter? What?
- Oh, the prannets. I had a personal transporter.
- Huh.
I'll do the paperwork in the morning.
Um, is it all right about Mrs. Tuttl...
Uh, Buttle's check?
- Uh-huh.
- Can I forget it?
- Yeah.
- Oh, what a relief.
I'm gonna have nightmares, you know.
- Oh, damn and blast!
- What's the matter?
I don't suppose you'd happen to know
how I can get round an I RQ/3, do you?
Ooh, all information
on third-level suspects is classified.
All inquiries through Information Retrieval,
and that's hopeless. They never tell you anything.
Come the time
they want something from us, oh, yes.
There is one way I could get round it.
I could accept my mother's promotion.
Yes.
No!
You can't.
You've just turned it down.
I didn't sign the form.
I did it for you.
- You didn't.
- I did.
You didn't!
I did!
What did you do that for?
It's what you wanted, isn't it?
Oh, I don't know.
I don't know what I want.
Come on,
before they turn the lights out.
There is one way round it.
I could always accept promotion
to Information Retrieval.
Sam!
Oh, Christ.
What are you doing?
What... My God! What's going on?
- Emergency procedures.
- Emergency procedures.!
- I haven't got an emergency!
- Yeah?
- This is an emergency!
- Have a nice day.
This has not been a recording.
Here. Sign that.
- What is it?
- A 27 B/6.
What do you think it is?
Where's he gone?
Spoor, come here.!
Look.! I got it.! I found it.!
Spoor! Spoor!
Come here, Spoor!
It's a bypass valve on this...
on the transformer.
Tuttle!
Tuttle. It's Tuttle.
You've had that scab Tuttle here,
ain't ya?
What are you talking about?
- Who fixed your ducts? Huh?
- Fixed your ducts, all right.
I told you before...
they fixed themselves.
Oh, yeah? Then where did this
come from, eh?
Out of your nostril? Eh?
Nostrils, eh?
Central Services.
They don't take kindly to sabotage.
Sabotage, huh?
Jesus, this place is in a terrible state.
Just a minute.!
You're not gonna leave it like this, are you?
Why not? All you gotta do
is blow your nose and it's fixed, innit?
That's right!
Well...
Oh, my...
Jesus!
What have you done with his body?
# Mrs. Ida Lowry requests
the pleasure of your company #
# At her apartment tonight #
# From 8:30 #
# To midnight #
# To celebrate the completion #
# Of her recent cosmetic #
#Surgery #
# Telegram ##
Um...
thanks.
- It's reply paid.
- Is it?
Oh. Um...
Two, three...
# Mother, I'm sorry, but I'm unable
to come to your party #
- You don't have to sing it.
- I don't?
No.
Oh. Sorry.
Aren't you a bit late?
I mean, the party started an hour ago.
Yeah. It's the backlog.
Everybody complains.
- Oh.
- Was it all right otherwise?
Mr. Helpmann, I'm keen to
get into Information Retrieval.
Mr. Helpmann, I'm dying
to get at this woman. No, no... Ohh!
Oh, God.
- Hold up.
- What? Who are you?
- Hey! What's going on?
- Where's your invitation?
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Mother! Mother!
Sam.
I'm so glad you came.
Come in.
- Mother?
- Come in.
Oh, God, Mother, is that you?
Of course.
Isn't it wonderful?
The bandages came off just this afternoon.
Come on, darling. Join in the fun.
Simply everybody's here.
Is Mr. Helpmann here?
- Would you stop shoving...
- Yes, he is.
Mr. Helpmann is here,
and he wants to talk to you.
Good. I want to talk to him.
He says that you're the first person
ever to refuse a promotion.
- Ah, well...
- He thinks you should see a doctor.
- Actually, Mother, I've decided...
- Oh, Louis! Louis, you know Sam.
Can you believe it?
It's just me and my little knife.
- Snip, snip, slice, slice.
- It's marvelous.
- Can you believe it?
- Congratulations.
- But this is just the beginning.
- Oh, really?
Oh, Christ, yes.
You've seen her with her clothes off.
Faces are a doddle
compared to tits and ass.
- No hairline.
- Oh, really, Louis!
I've been looking for you
everywhere, Ida.
Mother. Mother, I have to
talk to Mr. Helpmann.
- Oh, you stupid sod.
- Dear boy.
What do you think of your mother now?
It'll never last.
Excuse me.
Dr. Chapman,
did you say something?
That technique... I've tried it.
Oh, nice effect,
but highly unstable.
In six months
she'll look like Grandma Moses.
Now, see here, Chapman, at least mine
don't end up looking like they've been mugged.
Sam! Sam!
What have you done with his body?
Sam!
Sam?
- What on earth's happened to you?
- There was a little complication.
Dr. Chapman says it often happens
with a delicate skin like mine.
Nothing to worry about.
He's promised me these bandages
will be off in a jiffy.
- Actually, there's someone I want to meet.
- Oh, I know.
I know.
There we are.
I'm going to leave
you two lovebirds in peace.
Hello, Shirley.
- Oh, God.
- Come on!
Do you want a drink?
Oh. Hello.
Chase those years away!
Listen, Shirley...
your mother and my mother,
they seem to have got the idea that...
Look, I'm very flattered
and, uh, well...
I just don't want you to be
under any false impressions.
It's all right.
I don't like you either.
Sam.!
Jack.
Excuse me, Shirley.
I'm s... I'm sorry.
- Sam! You remember Alison?
- Evening.
Alison. Sam Lowry.
Old friend.
Alison, yes, of course.
- You look different.
- Well, I'm two years older.
- And she's been to Dr. Jaffe.
- Ah.
She doesn't like me telling people,
but, in fact, she's really pleased.
- I knew there was something different.
- Remember how they used to stick out?
What? Oh, yes.
Uh, well, rather.
- Always used to wonder if they were real.
- What, my ears?
Sorry?
Dr. Jaffe pinned her ears back.
Yes, that's what I...
Always used to wonder
if she wore falsies.
Ah! Mr. Helpmann.
False ears...
Mr. Helpmann!
- Hello, Jack.
- You remember my wife, Alison?
Yes, of course.
Barbara, isn't it?
- How are you?
- Well, actuall...
Barbara's very well, thank you, sir.
Very well indeed. How are you?
- Fine, thanks.
- Good.
Hello, Sam. Ida said you might be here.
Have you got a minute?
- Would you excuse us?
- Oh, no, of course.
Of course.
Come on, Alison... Barbara.
Sam.
I need your help.
Thanks very much, Sam.
Mr. Helpmann,
I'm glad to be of help.
- If I can help you...
- Ah, well, actually...
Oh.
Your father and I were very close.
Of course, Jeremiah was senior to me,
but we were close friends.
Especially after the bombing.
And I keep his name alive
at the office every day.
It's as though he's there
still speaking to me.
"'Ere I am.
J.H."
The ghost in the machine.
I know he would have
wanted me to help you.
And I promised your mother...
that I'd take you on to the team
at Information Retrieval.
But I gather that, um...
Well, actually, Mr. Helpmann, I've, uh...
I've changed my mind.
I've decided I'd accept the transfer...
if I'm not too late.
Too late?
That's for me to say.
Well... Well, then, I, uh...
Welcome to Information Retrieval.
Uh, my name's Lowry.
Sam Lowry.
I've been told to report
to Mr. Warrenn.
Thirtieth floor, sir.
You're expected.
Um, don't you want to search me?
No, sir.
- Want to see my I.D.?
- No need, sir.
- But I could be anybody.
- No, you couldn't, sir.
This is Information Retrieval.
The lift's arrived, sir.
I want that order rescinded!
Half as terrorists, the rest as victims.
Yes. No.
Definitely no!
- My name's Lowry, Mr. Warrenn. Sam Lowry.
- Ah, Lowry!
Yes. No. Cancel that. Okay.
- Glad to have you aboard. Yes.
- These requisitions...
- Sir, I'd like to point this out...
- No! Don't be ridiculous, Jenkins.
- About these invoices...
- Yes. Yes. Yes.
You'll like it up here.
Send that back.
We've got a crack team of...
Are they kidding? Decision makers.
No, in triplicate.
I'm expecting big things...
Two copies to Financial!
No. No.
Don't let Progress see those.
Between you and me, Lowry, this... No, no!
Department... Tell Records to get stuffed!
Is about to be upgraded and...
Ah! Here we are.
Your very own number
on your very own door.
And behind that door,
your very own office.
Congratulations, DZ/015.
Welcome to the team.
Yes! No! Cancel that!
Send two copies to Financial.!
Well, you can't borrow any more chairs!
There's only one left in here now,
and I need that to sit on!
What?
Oh.
Sorry.
Who are you?
My name's Lowry.
Sam Lowry.
Oh, yes.
The new boy from next door.
My name's Lime.
Harvey Lime.
Welcome to Expediting.
I say, look, would you mind
if I borrowed your computer console?
- What?
- Yes, I'll let you have it back in 10 minutes.
You want to take my console
into your office?
Yes. Just for a few minutes.
I- I'll tell you what.
You tell me what you want...
and I'll do it for you.
I'm a bit of a whiz on that thing.
Um...
all right.
Uh, I need some information
on a woman named Layton.
A woman, eh?
- I see.
- Yes.
I know her age and distinguishing marks,
but I need an address or a place of work.
This your dream girl, is it?
What? Um...
Look, let me use your console.
You must be joking.
When there's a woman involved,
there's no stopping me.
Let's have that sheet.
Sod it! It's broken!
You haven't switched it on.
Oh, yes.
Look, you're putting me off standing there.
- Why don't you go back to your office
and I'll give you a knock when I'm finished.
- Um...
Go on. I'm not going to elope with her.
All right.
Sam!
Sam.
Don't go.
Please.
Well?
Computers are my forte.
Let me see.
"Jillian Layton. Coloring: White.
Hair: Blonde. Eyes: Blue. Height: 5 foot 4.
Distinguishing marks:
Scar on left"...
Is this all you've got?
Best to take things slowly
where some women are concerned.
Let me see.
Hey! That's mine!
"Layton.
"Truck driver.
All inquiries, reference office
of 412/L, room 5001."
Ah, Lowry, glad I caught you.
No! Send that back!
- Mr. Warrenn.!
- Are you settling down?
I want this order rescinded.
There's a query about a personnel transporter
you took out from the pool.
Tell them no.
Tell them yes.
Or was it a personnel carrier
you took out from Transportation?
Send that up to Security.
Anyway, tidy it up, Lowry.
There's a good chap.
And get a new suit.
Don't you want the lift?
Can I help you?
No.! No.! No.! Please.!
I'm, uh... I'm looking for Officer 412/L.
He won't be very long now.
I thought so.
You may go in now.
Oh, uh, not that one.
That one. Yes.
Excuse me.
Are you Officer 412/L?
Excuse me!
Jack.
Sam.
Ah! I heard you were coming aboard.
Congratulations, "DZ/015."
Thanks.
Are you Officer 412/L?
Uh-huh. That's me.
Oh, and, Sam,
a very happy Christmas.
- Thanks, Jack.
- Are you settling in all right?
Yes, fine. Jack, I...
I need some information.
Oh, Sam, this is Information Retrieval,
not Information Dispersal.
Hey! Amy!
Don't throw the ball around in here.
I'm not Amy. I'm Holly.
Did I call you Amy, darling?
I'm sorry.
- A triplet?
- One of them, I think.
Barbara's taken the other two
Christmas shopping.
You're not going to keep
calling her Barbara, are you?
Why ever not?
Barbara's a perfectly good name, isn't it?
Don't you like it?
Yes, it's... fine.
Come on.
Let's get these together.
- Jack.
- Now bring me the blue one over there.
I need to find out about a woman.
Come on, Chloe, let's show Uncle Sam here
how we can make the word "cat." Shall we?
- I'm Holly.
- Sorry, love. So you are.
- Cat.
- This is her.
Layton.
Oh, shit.
- How much do you know about this?
- Uh, not much.
What does B58/732 mean to you?
- Buttle.
- I knew it.
You always were bloody quick, Sam.
Who else knows?
Warrenn? Helpmann?
I don't know.
I only know you got the wrong man.
Information Transit got the wrong man.
I got the right man.
The wrong man was delivered to me
as the right man.
I accepted him on good faith
as the right man. Was I wrong?
You killed Buttle?
Sam, there are very rigid parameters laid down
to prevent such things happening.
It wasn't my fault that Buttle's heart condition
didn't appear on Tuttle's file.
Come and look.
How you getting on?
- Jack.
- A, B, C...
- I really need to know about...
- Tuttle?
Well, we're gonna have to bring
Mr. Tuttle in, aren't we?
And interrogate him
at the same voltage as Mr. Buttle.
And juggle the books
in Electrical Banking.
- What has Tuttle done?
- We suspect him of, uh, freelance subversion.
A freelance subversive.
Then all I need to wrap up the case
is the Layton woman.
What has she done?
Well, she witnessed the Tuttle...
Um, the Buttle arrest.
Since then, she's been going around
making wild allegations...
obviously trying to exploit the situation.
She's working for someone,
and I don't think it's us.
- That's it. Over there, love.
- Terrorist?
Mr. Lint, the next customer has been delivered.
- Thank you, Myrtle.
- What are you gonna do
about the Layton woman?
Well, I put her on the detention list.
Security should have her here before 6:00.
What, here? So that she can
spill the beans inside the department?
Don't do that!
Jack, why don't I
try and get to her for you?
I'll, um... I'll deactivate her.
What does that mean, Sam? I don't want
to get involved in anything unsavory.
Trust me, Jack.
- Come on, darling. Put these away now.
Mummy'll be here soon.
- Let me have her file.
Look, trust me, Jack.
All right.
Come on here.
All right, but for Christ's sake,
don't lose it.
All right.
You sit down there, Mary.
Sam.
Don't worry.
I'll get to her.
You'll never get anywhere
in a suit like that.
Here.
Try this.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye!
Uh, but, Jack, I...
Put it on, big boy.
I won't look at your willy.
Oh, let him go.
Trier, isn't he?
Just... I've been to
the department of...
But you've stamped this form before.
Why won't you stamp it now?
You just said yourself, miss...
we've already stamped it.
No, no! Stop!
Up! Up! Up! Up! Up!
Oh, God.
Come on!
Shit!
Oi.!
Come out of there.
- What?
- That's the deputy minister's lift.
- I'm sorry. I'm in a hurry.
- Oi, come here.
Come here, sonny.
Let's see your I.D. Card, eh?
My I.D.? Oh, God.
This isn't my suit.
My name is Lowry. Sam Lowry.
Look, really, can't this wait?
No, sir. I'm going to have to
fill in a report on this.
Now, then, uh,
what is the date today?
It's the...
Oh, God, it'll have to wait!
Oi! Oi, you! Stop!
Come back here! Stop!
Aim!
Stop! Don't...
Up!
Well done, men.
Quick thinking.
Excellent work.
Um...
I'll take charge of her now.
Good. Good man.
Um, okay.
Uh... It's a...
classified matter...
and, um, I'll, uh...
I'll include your fine handling
of the situation in my report.
Great.
Uh, merry Christmas, Dawson.
Come along with me, please.
Please? Okay. Yes.
Well done, men. Excellent.
Good turnout. Nice.
Very good. Thank you.
No, no, no. This way, please.
Straight ahead.
This way. This way.
This way.
Just keep moving.
- Hey.! Stop.!
- What?
Come back here!
Pick up all these things!
- Come on.! Pick them up.!
- Geez... Oh...
Disgraceful.!
- Can't you read English?
- Ow! Get your bloody...
You illiterate foreign pig!
You come over here on your own...
...and think you can
mess up our streets!
Oh, God.
Stop!
That's it! Let's go!
Vroom! Vroom!
What are you doing?
For Christ's sake, keep moving!
- Get out of my cab.
- What?
Just drive!
You touched me.
Nobody touches me.
What are you... Oh, God!
Please! Please! Drive on!
Drive on, will you! For...
Oh, shit. Move over. I'll drive.
Don't touch that! Don't touch anything!
It's okay, Officer. Thank you. It's okay.
Got everything under control. Thank you.
Oh, shit. They're coming.
Listen, please drive. Drive.
Trust me. You are in terrible danger.
You are an embarrassment.
Please.
Please drive.
Trust me. Trust me.
Drive, and I'll explain everything.
Please...
get out of my cab.
- I'm sorry. I...
- Okay!
Okay, you've asked for it!
I'm Information Retrieval Officer D...
DZ/105!
And I'm arresting you as a...
Drive on, or I'll blast
your fucking head off!
Go!
Look, I'm, uh... I'm sorry about that.
I mean, uh, touching you
without permission.
But, um... Hello.
My name is Lowry.
Sam Lowry.
I... I'm... I've been, uh...
You won't believe this,
and I know it's going to sound incredible...
but, um... but I've been
dreaming about you.
No, not like that. I mean, I love you.
In my dreams I love you.
And, uh...
I mean... Extraordinary, isn't it?
Anyway, um...
y- y-you...
You don't believe me, do you?
You, um...
You probably think I-I-I-I'm bonkers, right?
Mad. Raving.
No! No, I think
you're very attractive.
What?
Yeah. Yeah, sit back.
Let me have a look at you.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Good-looking, sexy.
Just my type.
I don't believe you.
Why not?
Well, I-I... I just don't deserve
such terrific luck.
Damn right.
Help!
I love...
You don't trust me, do you?
Oh!
Oh, my God.
We shouldn't have come here.
I got a job to do!
- But they'll be lying in wait.
- Oh, Christ, you're paranoid.
You've got no sense of reality.
Wait, wait, wait! Wait!
We should take the lorry
and get away!
- Yeah? Where to?
- Anywhere, as fast as possible.
- There isn't anywhere!
- Just far away!
That's not far enough!
But... Wait!
Jill!
What's in the, uh, parcel?
- Christmas present.
- Oh.
It's heavy.
Heavy Christmas present.
- You don't trust me, open it.
- No!
No, no, it's, uh... it's fine.
I'd spoil the wrapping.
Anyway, if I want you to trust me,
then it's only fair that I should trust you. Right?
Doesn't it bother you, the sort of things
you do at Information Retrieval?
What?
I suppose you'd rather
have terrorists.
Here's one now.
How many terrorists have you met, Sam?
Actual terrorists?
- Actual terrorists?
- Yeah.
Well...
It's only my first day.
- Uh-oh.
- A roadblock.
- What are we gonna do?
- Stay calm.
Don't slow down.
Don't slow down!
Don't stop. Please.
Please do as I say. Go.
Go! Straight ahead! Go!
- Go! Go! Go!
- What are you doing, you stupid asshole?
Whoo!
We did it! We did it!
We broke right through!
We did it! Whee, whee, whee, whee!
- Faster! Don't let them see you! Just go!
- Get off of me!
Keep going! Keep going! Faster!
- Get your foot down on it! Move!
- Stay off of it!
No!
Get off!
Shit!
Oh, no.
Faster! Faster!
- What if we lose the house, yeah?
- Don't touch anything!
Don't touch it!
We did it! We did it!
Oh, no.
And what would you like for Christmas?
My own credit card.
Hmm.
- Why have we come here?
- Go away!
- Look, why don't we go back to my flat.
- Forget it.
- You don't trust me?
- Trust you? Trust you?
A man who hijacks my truck,
loses me my job...
has every security man in town
looking for me?
- Of course I trust you.
- I was only trying to help.
- Yeah!
- Okay. Okay.
You don't trust me, I don't trust you.
- What's in that parcel?
- Oh, Jesus.
You saved it from the lorry.
It must be something very special.
I saved you from the lorry.
You're not something "very special."
- How can you... I'm gonna open it.
- Don't touch that!
Sam! It's me!
And Shirley.!
Mrs. Terrain.
- That should hold it.
- Sam?
Hello, Shirley.
My God, what on earth's
happened to you now?
My complication
had a little complication.
But Dr. Chapman
says I'll soon be up...
and bounding about
like a young gazelle.
You buying a Christmas present
for your mother?
What?
Oh, um, yes.
A little something.
Shirley and I come here
"wegularlarly."
We love romantic lingerie.
Really?
Sam, picture me in these.
- Oh, my God.
- Sam, where are you going?
Sam! Sam!
Jill?
Jill!
Oh, my God.
Are you all right?
Well, you don't deserve to be!
What a bloody stupid thing!
How could you?
Look at these people! My God!
It was a bomb.
I should have opened it.
I sat there with it next... I...
What a stupid thing.
There's your bomb, asshole!
Bribes...
for official monkeys like you.
Oh.
Go on.
Make yourself useful.
Here.
Don't touch her! She's hurt!
Damn it!
- Don't touch her!
- No.!
Stop!
Sam, no! Sam! Behind you!
These helmets don't half
make your scalp itch.
Oh, don't mention it.
And they make you sweat.
Half the time
I can't ever see where I'm going.
There's a great Niagara
of perspiration coming down.
Well, I'm lucky.
I got these thick eyebrows.
That keeps it up
and channels it out to the ears.
Yeah. Who's he?
Oh, I don't know.
Somebody from Information Retrieval.
They're always hangin' around
in Lingerie.
Where is she? Huh?
Jill, is that you?
Uh... Excuse me, sir.
That is government property.
Oh, Jill.
Jill! Answer me!
I'm looking for a girl
with blonde hair.
She's medium height, green eyes.
I don't know, sir.
They check all that at the depot.
Uh, we can't allow that, sir.
It's more than our job's worth.
Jill!
Jill, you must be here! Jill!
Look, sir, you can fill in an application form,
sir, if you're a relative.
Now, do stop, sir. Please.
Jill? Jill?
Oh, dear, oh, dear, oh, dear.
Sorry about that, sir.
Regulations.
This is a black eye
for the department, Lowry.
I don't care how you behaved
when you were at Records.
Information Retrieval
is an executive branch.
We're proud of our reputation
and we protect it.
Damn it, Lowry! That convoy of personnel
carriers is still not accounted for!
I thought I told you to deal with it.
And what the hell is this mess?
An empty desk is an efficient desk.
Good God.
Queries from Security.
Searches from Central Banking
about a check?
Clarification notices from Accounting
concerning unreturned receipts?
- Mr. Warrenn, I have to find out about...
- Get up!
I don't know what's going on here, Lowry.
But don't think you can intimidate us
with your friends and relatives in high places.
Now shape up!
Lime, I have to use your computer.
Sorry.
A bit busy at the moment.
You seem to have rather a lot
to get on with yourself.
Shit.
Come off it, Jack.
Of course you can check
to see if she's been arrested.
I'm sorry, Sam. I'm afraid this case has become
much more complicated since last we... talked.
But she's innocent, Jack.
She's done nothing wrong.
Tell that to the wives of the security men
she blew up this afternoon.
She's not alone in all this.
We've just had a report in that Tuttle
has wrecked an entire flat...
and sabotaged
adjacent Central Services.
As a matter of fact,
it looks like on your block.
I should keep my eyes open
if I were you, Sam. Bye.
But, Jack, you don't really think Tuttle
and the girl are in league, do you?
I do.
Everything's connected
all along the line.
Cause and effect.
That's the beauty of it.
Our job is to trace the connections
and, uh, reveal them.
This whole Buttle-Tuttle confusion
was obviously planned from the inside.
Bye-bye.
Oh, but, Jack!
She's innocent, Jack.
Sam, we've always been close,
haven't we?
Yes, Jack?
Well, until this all blows over
just stay away from me.
But...
Oh, my God.
You.
It's you.
What's happening?
Your thermostat's gone,
and then some.
And then some!
What's happened to my flat?
Hello? What?
It's for you.
- But as you don't live here anymore...
- What?
Absolutely.
Do you know what this is?
This is an H2206...
authorizing the compulsory,
temporary requisitioning of this flat...
for our necessary repairs.
- Repairs!
- What?
- No! You...
- Don't forget your receipt.
- Oh! Oh! Oh!
- No, sir. Don't forget your receipt.
I'm sorry, but I'm a bit
of a stickler for paperwork.
He's a stickler for paperwork, sir.!
Bastards!
Tuttle.
- What are you doing?
- Shh.
Phew-ee.
Oh, God.
- Jesus Christ!
- The smell! Stop!
Filling up with...
Oh, God.
Oh, Jesus!
Oh!
Shit!
We're all in it together, kid.
Jill. Jill.!
Jill. Oh, God.
Are you all right?
What happened to you after...
Your face. Are you hurt?
Um, no, I-I'm fine.
It's... Well...
I've been worried sick about you.
- Who was that?
- That's a friend of mine. He...
Oh, God. Holy shit.
We'd better get out of here quick.
Come on. Quietly.
Look out. Here. Take this.
Looks big.
Here.
Quick. Quick.
- Are you sure this is all right?
- Yes. Yes, certain.
My mother's away for Christmas.
She's spending it at the plastic surgeon's.
The wraps come off tomorrow.
Lock the door after me.
Don't answer the phone to anyone.
I won't be long.
- Where are you going?
- I know a way to save you.
- Trust me. I can do it.
- But you can't go without me.
Excuse me, Dawson. Could you put me through
to Mr. Helpmann's office, please?
I'm afraid I can't, sir.
You have to go through the proper channels.
And you can't tell me what the proper channels are
because that's classified information.
I'm glad to see the ministry is continuing
its tradition of recruiting the brightest and best, sir.
Thank you, Dawson.
- Good night, Mr. Lime.
- Good night, Dawson.
# The first Noel #
# The angels did say #
# Was to certain poor shepherds #
#In fields as they lay #
#In fields where they #
No, no, no, Arthur!
You're flat on the "G."
It's your breathing.
Now take a deep breath after "Noel."
Ready? One, two, three.
# The first Noel #
# The angels did say ##
'Ere I am,J.H.
The ghost in the machine.
E- R-E-I-A-M-J-H.
Mr. Helpmann.
Mr. Helpmann?
Jill.
Jill?
Who's there?
What do you think?
Is it me?
Well?
You don't exist anymore.
I've killed you.
Jill Layton is dead.
Care for a little necrophilia?
Hmm?
Yee-hah! Yee-hah!
Merry Christmas.
Uh...
Something for an executive?
Sh-She's dead.
This is just a friend of mine.
She's...
- What are you...
- No!
- Oh, my God!
- No! Sam!
"N3/HK/608, you are charged
with the following:
"Giving aid and comfort
to the enemies of society,:
"Attempting to conceal
a fugitive from justice;
"passing confidential documents
to unauthorized personnel...
"viz I.R. DossierJillian Layton;
"destroying government property viz
an indeterminate number of personnel carriers;
"taking possession under false pretenses
of said personnel carriers;
"forging the signature
of the head of Records, third department;
"intention to misdirect ministry funds
to the form of a check to A. Buttle...
"through unauthorized channels;
"tampering Central Services
supply ducts;
"obstruction of forces, Law and Order,
in the exercise of their duty;
"bringing into disrepute
the good name of the government...
"and the standing within the community
of the Department of Information Retrieval;
"attempting to disrupt the Ministry of Information
Retrieval's internal communicating system;
wasting ministry time and paper."
Now, either you plead guilty...
to, say, seven or eight of the charges...
which is going to help keep costs down
within your means...
or you can borrow a sum, to be negotiated
from us, at a very competitive rate.
We can offer you something,
let's say 11 and a half percent over 30 years...
but you will have to buy insurance
to qualify for this scheme.
Or, if you prefer something
more specific...
say, against electrical charges
over £70...
All you're requested to do at this stage
is to sign this form.
Think carefully before you decide.
Looking ahead in financial matters
is always a wise course.
Sam, what are we going to do with you?
Where is Jill?
I've got to find her.
Please. Please, you've got to
get me out of here.
I understand, Sam.
I know exactly how you feel.
So I've brought you
a bottle of barley water.
Oh, please help me.
I assure you, Sam,
I'm doing everything within my power.
But the rules of the game
are laid down.
We all have to play by them.
Even me.
It's all a mistake.
You've got to understand that.
Yes, well, from the department's point of view,
you're certainly a bit of an own goal, but...
I'm not a terrorist.
You must know that.
Please, please get me out of here.
Sam, information retrieval
is expensive.
You're running up an enormous bill
by not cooperating.
Please.
Please, Mr. Helpmann.
Help me find Jill.
Jill.
Yes.
Sam, I think I ought to tell you.
I'm afraid she's upped stumps
and retired to the pavilion.
Thrown in the towel.
Dead?
Yes.
It's all a bit confusing,
but it seems she was killed...
resisting arrest.
No. It's all right.
I did that.
The odd thing is,
it appears to have happened twice.
Bit of a disputed call, I'm afraid.
Twice?
So, there you are.
All I can say is, don't fall at the last fence,
the finishing post in sight.
See you in the paddock.
Do cooperate.
Think of your mother.
Good luck.
Keep your eye on the ball.
Gotta go.
Can't keep the orphans waiting.
Don't fight it, son.
Confess quickly.
If you hold out too long,
you could jeopardize your credit rating.
695/6.
Thank you.
Jack?
Jack.
Jack. Jack!
Shut up.
Jack. Jack, I'm innocent.
Please.
- Help me.
- Bastard.
Jack.
Jack, this is all a mistake.
Please, Jack.
Take that mask off.
You stupid bastard.
- Jack.
- How could you do this to me?
Jack, I'm frightened.
How do you think I feel, you shit?
- Jack...
- Shut up!
This is a professional relationship.
Jack.
Jack, no, you can't.
No, Jack, please.
Jack, no.! Don't.!
Please, Jack.! No.!
- You okay?
- Tuttle!
Call me Harry.
Let's go!
Here. Here.
Ah, Mr. Lowry.
So pleased you could make it.
Right this way.
It's a sad loss.
Your mother was with her at the end.
The gift of eternal life.
Mrs. Terrain has just received
that most wonderful of gifts.
She came to us physically new.
She goes hence from us
not so physically new.
But the spirit never grows old.
Madame Lowry.
Mother.
Oh. Sam.
Mother. Mother!
Stop calling me that.
Mother! Mother, please!
- Is this guy bothering you?
- Oh. Tsk, tsk, tsk, tsk.
Mother!
Go away.
This is a very sacred moment.
He's got away from us, Jack.
Afraid you're right, Mr. Helpmann.
He's gone.
Well...
# Then #
# Tomorrow was another day #
# The morning found me miles away #
# With still a million things to say #
#Now #
#As twilight gleams the sky above #
#Recalling thrills of our love #
# There's one thing I'm certain of #
#Return #
#I will #
# To old #
#Brazil ##