Some of this is legend, but
at least this much is fact.
When rioting citizens of
France destroyed the Bastille...
they discovered within its
records this mysterious entry:
Prisoner number
6-4-3-8-9000.
The man in the iron mask.''
You dead yet?
Aramis!
Porthos is-
l'm sorry, my dears. You
would have enjoyed it too.
- He's hung like a donkey.
- So are you.
- Really?
- Yeah.
lt has been asleep so long,
l've forgotten about it.
Okay, go on now. Leave
His Holiness alone.
l'll bring you back tomorrow
when he's in a better mood.
Go on, ladies.
Stop praying and revel with me, Aramis.
l need my spirits
lifted. l'm old. l'm weak.
- My strength is gone.
- Porthos.
- l'm praying.
- l just said you're praying.
Are you deaf too? l know
you're blind because...
if you'd seen the tits that
just walked out of here...
you'd have tears in your eyes.
Sometimes there are more important
things to life than a good pair of tits.
Really?
Hey, Aramis...
if you can name me one
thing, one single thing...
that is more sublime than the feel...
of a plump, pink nipple
between my lips...
l'll build you a new cathedral.
Forgiveness.
Forgiveness?
Forgive me.
Am l forgiven?
l observe your forgiveness isn't
sweeter than a plump nipple.
Don't you understand?
l'm trying to pray!
You're always praying!
D'Artagnan!
Oh! D'Artagnan!
- How are you, young pup?
- Porthos.
You interrupted a simple
theological discussion.
- So l see.
- Welcome. Sit.
l wish that l could.
l come upon the king's
business. He wishes to see you.
Still you serve him loyally,
even though the people...
throw rotten eggs at his royal emblem.
Look at you. You look so young.
And l feel so old.
King says immediately.
One for all, D'Artagnan.
And all for one.
We were all Musketeers once, eh?
l wonder how Athos is doing.
Relax, Raoul. After all, you're my son.
How could any woman resist you?
When will you ask her?
Today, as we arrive, or
perhaps when we are leaving.
When l think about
it, l get so confused.
Will this help?
Mother's ring.
l can't take this. lt's yours.
She died giving you
to me. l want to die...
knowing it's on the finger
of the woman my son loves.
Go. Bring back your fiance.
Your Majesty, the
attack will come at dawn.
No, no. Do not underestimate the Dutch.
These troops will be cut off
here, so shift them here and here.
And then we outnumber them
there. Yes, send that on its way.
- Your Majesty-
- The yellow sash.
As your advisors,
we feel it is our-
- Our duty.
- Yes, our duty...
to inform you that
there are riots in Paris.
Riots?
But Paris is the most
beautiful city in the world.
Why should my people feel
anything but pride and contentment?
Well, of course, Your Majesty. l'm
sure they are content and proud.
But they are also starving.
Your Majesty, if we
distributed some of the food...
that has been reserved for the army...
there would be plenty
of time to gather more-
Father Aramis...
His Majesty is experiencing
some difficulty with the Jesuits.
- The Jesuits?
- They have declared that...
His Majesty's wars are unjust
and the source of public hunger.
Then perhaps His Majesty
should speak to their leader.
Yes, but who is he?
No one can keep secrets
like the Jesuits can.
Your Majesty.
You are a priest, but
once you were a Musketeer.
l, like my father before
me, have trusted you...
with the gravest of missions.
l want you to find out who the
secret leader of the Jesuits is.
And when you have...
for God and for France,
l wish you to kill him.
l know this is a terrible thing l
ask, especially from a priest, but-
Can you accept this
mission and keep it private?
When l discover the identity
of this Jesuit rebel...
l will kill both him
and the man who told me.
Once a Musketeer, always a Musketeer.
Now, about these riots.
We have stocks on the
wharves right now, don't we?
We can distribute that.
But, Majesty, that food is spoiling.
That is why it was not sent to the army.
Then you must hurry.
What an excellent idea, Your Majesty.
Look at the stitching on that one.
Don't they look glorious?
Not so glorious as you.
Who is that?
Raoul, the son of Athos.
Francois, your taste may
run to young soldiers...
but l was referring to
the beauty next to him.
Her name is Christine.
Majesty.
What is it now? Assassins
falling from the skies?
The pig chase plans were kept from me.
D'Artagnan, look at
the faces of these men.
They admire and fear you. With the
great D'Artagnan watching over me...
who in France would be possibly
such a fool as to try and do me harm?
A fool's blade can be
sharper than his brain.
Let us play a game.
Let us pretend as if
l am king and you are...
the captain of my Musketeers.
Let us behave as if my wish is law...
and my wish is to enjoy this party...
as should you.
Ladies.
Christine, ever since l arrived-
- Monsieur? Mademoiselle?
- No, thank you.
Captain, may l present
Christine Bellefort.
D'Artagnan is my father's best friend.
l am honored that you
have granted my request...
for a commission in the Musketeers,
that l may follow my father and you.
The honor is mine.
One for all.
And all for one.
l love you.
And l love you.
l'll never be a rich man, but
you'll always have my heart.
Then l am richer than the king.
Then l have something to give you
that once belonged to my mother.
We offer a contest of
cunning and agility.
Behold our unicorn.
Whoever captures our unicorn...
shall win its treasure.
Now, to the chase. l command you all!
The pendant will be yours.
Christine, isn't it? l would've
thought it was impossible...
but l do believe the excitement of this
chase has made you even more beautiful.
Sire, l thank you.
You blush. You do not wish to
look beautiful for your king?
No, sire.
l mean, yes, yes. Of course, sire.
- l mean that, you are-
- lt's all right.
l understand that you're not
accustomed to these surroundings.
But that is a condition
we can happily remedy.
One such as you would fit
nicely as a lady-in-waiting.
His Majesty is very, very kind...
but l'm engaged to Raoul...
or will be when he manages to ask me.
You would choose a soldier-
a soldier who has not yet
proposed, above a king?
l could only be faithful to my heart.
But how faithful is that heart to you?
Wait, Christine.
Feed your people.
Jesuits.
Get me a general.
Her Majesty wishes a word with you.
Your Majesty.
l understand you saved
my son's life today.
God smiled upon us, Your Majesty.
And you are not hurt?
- No, my lady.
- That is good.
Captain.
Raoul, son of Athos, had withdrawn
his request to join the Musketeers.
- You have improved.
- lt's been so long.
So it has, my friend.
- What's the occasion?
- As you say, it's been too long.
When the great D'Artagnan visits,
he must be offered the best wine.
And if the great Athos offers,
the great D'Artagnan must drink.
l'm sorry l haven't been to
see you lately, my friend.
Head of the king's bodyguards?
That must keep you busy.
Especially with this king.
Still, l should have come
to see you more often.
l belong to the past, when the uniforms
were black and grown men wore them.
At least it gives you more
time to practice your violin.
And feel sorry for myself.
My son is grown. He's
proposed to a wonderful girl.
He's joined the Musketeers. All the
errors of my life are made right in him.
And now, for the life l've always
wished him, he's leaving my home.
Out celebrating all night.
Look who's come to visit.
What's the matter?
l cannot risk making her a widow
just as l ask to make her a wife.
l've been recalled to my regiment.
But that makes no sense.
You've already served at the front.
Has there been some disaster?
Has everyone else been recalled?
l believe that the king's
eye has fallen on Christine.
lt's true the king has noticed her, but
l don't think it has anything to do-
lt has everything to do
with it. The king is a dog.
- Athos.
- A dog and a coward.
But l am neither, and so l go.
Does the king have
trouble finding women?
Does he have trouble filling his bed?
l served his father.
Until l retired, l served him.
And now, to seduce a woman
who will mean nothing to him...
once he has had her, he would
put my son's life in danger?
You knew this was happening.
You knew, and that's why you came!
- l knew your temper.
- You came to restrain me?
To bring you hope.
l will speak to the king personally.
l have not yet lost faith that he may
become the king we all wish him to be.
You don't know what it's
like to have a son...
to have kissed his hair
and smelled his breath...
as he slept, to have watched him grow.
Yes. Fatherhood is a blessing...
l can only imagine.
l have never known a finer man than
you, nor cared more for a friend.
But if this king harms my
son merely to take a lover...
then this king will become my enemy.
And so will any man that stands
between that enemy and me.
Then l must hurry...
for l treasure your son...
as l treasure you.
Guard the gate. Captain.
The people are saying the food the
king ordered us to distribute is rotten.
They're attacking
Musketeers all over the city.
Get the gate!
- We'll fire a volley into them.
- No. Close the gates. Do not fire.
lt's D'Artagnan.
Citizens of Paris, listen to me.
- l am one of you.
- We're starving!
They give us garbage
not even fit for rats!
Listen to me.
Listen to me, l beg you!
You're right. lt is rotten.
l will speak to the king myself.
You have my word on it.
And you will release those men,
for they serve France and you.
Oh, Louis, you were right.
A woman has never known love...
until she has known the love of a king.
l'm hungry.
l'll have some food brought.
l like to eat alone.
By the way, you'll be leaving tomorrow.
These passageways were made
for the king's security...
not so you can startle me to death.
lt is for your security
that l've come, Your Majesty.
l already know about the rioting.
Your people are most
anxious to love you...
but they are eating rotten
food, and sometimes none at all.
Rotten food?
Well, l'll deal with that decisively.
There is another matter
of a more personal nature.
You are constantly
surrounded by beautiful women.
- Do you love any of them?
- Quite frequently, actually.
And they love you?
How do you know that...
when a woman gives you her
most intimate embrace...
that it is you and not your
crown that she pulls to her heart?
You think my affairs are empty.
l think that it is
possible for one man...
to love one woman all his life
and be the better for it, yes.
You may be right.
Perhaps l haven't met a woman with
a heart like my own until recently.
Would that be Christine?
lt is good that you watch me, but
l fear you watch me too closely.
Did you send Raoul to the war so
that you could be free to pursue her?
- Do you question my honor?
- No, l do not question your honor.
lt's you l care about.
Raoul will return soon.
You have my word.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
l am a young king...
but l am king.
Then be a good king, Your Majesty.
You're the new chief advisor. Execute
him for distributing rotten food.
And the next time there
are rioters, shoot them.
Over there.
Wait.
Please take this to
the royal dispatchers.
l'll get you some water
in a moment, Mother.
His Majesty regrets to inform
you that Raoul, son of Athos...
has been killed in action.
Sir, a casualty report came.
Does Athos know of this?
Athos, my friend.
Stop there, you traitor!
Listen to me!
The cannons killed Raoul.
Do not add your own
death to this tragedy.
l beg you.
Get back.
You're the traitor.
See to the wounded.
Does your new apartment suit you?
Sire, when you sent for me
after the news of Raoul...
l just came to ask for your help.
l have no way to feed my family.
- My father is dead and my mother has-
- A sickness of the lungs.
And your sister has early
signs of the condition.
But my physician has seen
them both and is optimistic.
They will recover well
at my country estate.
Oh, Your Majesty.
l know this day for you...
the Earth has spun round more than once.
And you must still feel it spinning.
Let us sit at a quiet dinner and see
if we may not bring it to a pause.
Listen to me.
You've lost someone
dear to your heart...
and l have no desire for you to sit
here trying to turn that heart to stone.
l only ask you this:
that whatever you feel tonight...
you allow yourself to
share it openly with me.
To good health.
You are so beautiful.
l cannot do this.
l hope you know that there is
more of me to love than a crown.
Of all the wonders l have seen...
l have never looked upon
anything as beautiful as you.
Aramis, is this the way to hell?
Hell may be our destination,
but not this trip.
A tomb.
We are in a tomb?
The secrecy is
regrettable, but necessary.
Please, sit.
When we were young men...
and we saw injustice, we fought it.
Now we know that some problems
cannot be solved with a sword.
And some can't be settled without one.
Here is the problem at hand.
The Jesuits oppose Louis' wars...
and the starvation that results.
So, Louis has ordered me...
to discover the true identity of
the general of the Jesuit order...
and to kill him.
You should let the secret
general worry about that.
Problem is that...
l am he.
l am the general of
the Order of Jesuits.
What do you propose to do?
- Replace the king.
- l cannot listen to this.
- lt can't be done.
- lt can.
- l know the way.
- l am with you.
- So am l.
- No.
l need you. All for one, one for all.
You cannot ask me to betray
my king. l have sworn an oath.
When a king is dishonorable, you
are removed from your oath of honor.
An oath is an oath precisely
because it cannot be removed.
Why do you follow him? Why?
What we fought for is greater
than king or rank or reward!
What do you fight for now?
l fight for the belief that every
man can be better, even Louis.
Whatever the plan, l am with you.
The next time we meet,
one of us will die.
Athos, wait.
Even were l not a priest, l
could see that your heart...
carries a secret weight...
and that it is hurting
you to bear it alone.
l cannot betray my king.
l will defend him with my life.
Then God go with you...
for none of us will.
l understand that there was an
incident at the Musketeer's gate...
where a man came intent on killing me.
ls it our policy now to allow
would-be assassins to go free?
What he wished to kill was his own pain.
His son is dead.
l can think of nothing worse.
- What about losing your king?
- That depends on the king.
When l became a Musketeer, l was
told that each time l drew my sword...
l should consider not
what l was killing...
but what l was allowing to live.
Do you know who told me that?
Athos.
Now if he has become our enemy...
we should ask ourselves why.
Well, Athos is gone.
Porthos and Aramis are missing too.
You know them better than anyone.
Are they a threat to me?
lf they are a threat, then we need
not seek them out. They will find us.
Not if you find them first.
- Who is this, then?
- Chi?
He says he's a replacement.
He says it's only one day a month
when the prisoner gets confession.
The usual priest is too sick to move.
lt is my confession day.
l'm sorry, you've never seen
me before. l must shock you.
l am a friend. l'm here to help you.
- What are you doing?
- lt is an escape.
Your escape to freedom.
Who is this?
He is you.
He says he just fell stone dead
as he was reading him the Mass.
l never thought he'd last this
long. How could he just keel over?
He says the prisoner has a fever
just like the other priest does.
Plague?
They brought plague in here?
Get him out of here, now!
No last rites! Get away!
We could chisel it off...
and see who he was.
No one will ever know.
He says burn it or we'll all get plague.
l think he's right.
Don't touch me!
Get out.
Stay back! He's got plague! Get out!
Hurry up!
Get away.
Go away. Hurry.
My God.
Jesuits. They're mine.
Here.
Drink.
lt's all right.
l have waited six years...
to ask this question.
Why was this done to me?
You don't know?
What do you remember?
l lived in a country house.
l had guardians, an old
woman and a priest...
but no friends.
Then they came and
took me to the prison.
- Who came?
- A man in black.
l never saw his face.
But he took me to the prison...
and he put me into the mask.
And you don't know why?
For days l shouted,
''What have l done?''
Then l realized that there
was something about my face...
which had to be hidden, but
l never knew what it was.
What is your name?
The old woman called me Philippe.
These men are going to help
clean you up. They won't harm you.
Thank you.
Thank you for your kindness.
And why are you so glum?
l expected action. There
was no killing, no fighting.
l was useless.
l grow tired of this attitude.
You're surrounded by beauty...
by intrigue, by danger.
What more could a man want?
Look around you.
The robins are singing.
The pigeons are cooing.
Can't you listen to their song?
There's plenty of food in the country,
since Louis sends it all to the army.
l have no appetite for food.
l'm wasting away.
Even women don't interest me anymore.
No, say good-bye to
Porthos, for he is gone.
Who is he?
You seek facts where you
should be seeking the truth.
You're not my priest, Aramis. You
would not be, even if l had one.
That's bitter.
The loss of Raoul...
and of D'Artagnan...
who you held as a
brother, and now you hate.
What gives you the right to judge me
and to play God with the lives of others?
Are you so much holier
than everyone else?
Yes, there is that, but also because
l'm more intelligent than anybody else.
- What is it?
- Kidney stones.
lt hurts when l piss.
lt hurts when l shit.
l'm just a fat old fart with
nothing to live for anymore.
l'm going to hang myself
as soon as l'm sober.
Come on.
He's ready.
The greatest mystery of life...
is who we truly are.
Yes.
l'm going to tell you the secret that's
been kept from you your whole life.
lt began the night King Louis was born.
l remember that night.
D'Artagnan, Athos and l were dining.
D'Artagnan was dead drunk- the only
time l've ever seen him like that.
But l was on duty.
l was summoned to a rear
door of the palace...
where the queen's own priest
placed a baby in my arms.
Do you understand this,
Athos? lt confuses me.
The queen had given
birth to twins that night.
And the child l carried
was the younger of the two.
Another. lt's another.
Suddenly, the old king
discovered he had two heirs.
He'd seen enough kingdoms torn
apart by feuding brothers...
so he decided, for the sake of
peace, to make one disappear.
You, Philippe.
He ordered your true
identity kept from you.
On his deathbed, he revealed your
existence to Louis and your mother.
She had been told by her own
priest that you had died at birth.
She blamed herself for
ever believing it...
and she wished to
restore your birthright.
But now Louis was king.
He was afraid to kill you.
For his whole claim of power rested
on the sanctity of royal blood.
So, instead, he devised a way
to keep you forever hidden.
For my country...
for my king...
l bought peace...
with your life.
And with my soul.
One day...
l will ask for your forgiveness.
But not until l have restored you...
to what is yours.
Restored?
We will replace Louis with Philippe.
That is your plan?
Exchanging one for the
other? lt's ludicrous!
lt's brilliant. What did
you imagine we were up to?
Revolution! Open war!
- Blood in the streets.
- At least it's a change.
Physical resemblance is but a beginning.
Louis has an arrogance, a manner-
- Which can be adopted.
- And people close to him.
Do you imagine that l've
not considered everything?
Have you considered that it is
not only our lives that you risk?
- lt is Philippe's as well.
- Yes, and like us, he has a choice.
What about it, Philippe?
All those years in prison.
Were they for nothing?
Or have they given you reserves
of strength unlike ordinary men?
You have the chance to be a king...
if you have the heart
to take that chance.
Do you have that heart?
l-
Your Majesty, a box has arrived
with strict instructions...
that its contents are
for your eyes alone.
Take this to my mother.
My son.
Please forgive me.
l can never make it right.
My lady.
lf anyone sees, it is death.
lf l don't kiss you, l'll die anyway.
l cannot bear to see you cry.
Please.
Tell me what's wrong.
l know that to love you is
a treason against France...
but not to love you is a
treason against my heart.
Then we will both die traitors.
More wine.
How is he?
Exhausted.
He's had a long day.
- Aramis-
- More wine!
You must reconsider this plan.
Philippe is like a child.
He cannot possibly be ready-
- You can do it.
- No.
- Yes, you can.
- ln one year, maybe two.
Three weeks.
The king is having a
ball, a masquerade ball.
A swirl of people, their faces covered.
lt is our perfect opportunity
and maybe the only one.
Philippe could be discovered
at any time. And what then?
More wine! Where is everybody?
No, it's no use.
- My sword is bent.
- lt'll be all right.
You're just taking a
while to get started.
- l can make your sword straight.
- No, it's dead.
l'm useless.
Three weeks to learn
all that he must know?
For 16 years he was
educated as a gentleman.
And for six more, he lived
in that mask, not knowing why.
Now he knows those who should have
loved him tore him from his birthright...
and threw him into loneliness and pain.
You grow fond of him. That's good.
Do not play God with me.
Nothing can replace Raoul.
What is Porthos doing?
Walking into the barn
naked, or so it would seem.
But what is he doing?
About to hang himself. He's been
threatening to do it for months.
Hang himself?
A sign from God.
lf Porthos is determined
to end his life...
then he's bound to find
the opportunity, isn't he?
Good-bye, cruel world.
Farewell to useless Porthos.
- What was that?
- lt's all right. l sawed the beam.
l'm a genius, not an engineer.
ls he still there?
Aramis, you did this!
You knew l would try hanging myself
and you sawed the beam! Admit it!
Of course l knew. You've
been moping around for months.
Now that you've tried
to kill yourself...
you can stop boring everybody
and be useful for a change.
Well.
And put some clothes on.
Well, okay.
l've worn this mask so long,
l don't feel safe without it.
l will sit with you.
l can't sleep either.
l've been in prison for six years.
You freed me.
But now you're asking me
to enter another prison.
The palace is hardly a prison.
See those farm maids working there?
See the one holding the lamb?
l would tend lambs with
her for the rest of my life.
We're offering you a chance to be king.
You're offering me a chance
to pretend to be king.
A king that you hate.
Not everyone hates him.
Don't you?
Why should l become him?
Until you give me a
reason, l won't do it.
l cannot.
We're all God's instruments,
whether we like it or not.
All we can do is keep faith.
Even though l admit l
sometimes find that hard to do.
We all fail at faith, you know?
That's why we must eat,
drink and make love to life.
As king, if you like plow maids...
you can have a thousand.
- You missed the point.
- What point?
Philippe is right.
We haven't given him a reason
to do what we ask of him.
l understand your reason.
You understand my reason?
Porthos told me about your son.
And you think that's why l'm here?
Yes, Raoul is my reason,
but not in the way you think.
Once all of us believed
in spending our lives...
in the service of something
greater than ourselves.
Aramis had his faith.
Porthos, his lust for life.
D'Artagnan, his devotion.
And l had Raoul.
But we all had a common dream-
that one day we would finally be able
to serve a king worthy of the throne.
lt is what we dreamt...
what we bled for...
and what we have spent a
lifetime waiting to see.
l taught Raoul to believe in that dream.
And now my son is dead.
So l am here to find out
if his life was in vain.
And the only one who can
answer that question is you.
lf we fail in this attempt...
and we probably will...
l'll be honored to die beside you.
And you.
This has arrived for you.
My darling Christine.
ln parting from you, l
have left heaven for hell.
l go because l can
love you only in honor.
You've created in me the
need to be a better man.
l will love through heaven or hell...
if that is where l must go...
to love you as you should be loved.
Remember that and
give yourself no blame.
Yours forever, Raoul.
What's wrong?
What's the matter?
l received a letter from Raoul.
He sent it to the palace...
knowing that he would die...
and l would be here.
How would he know that?
l-
l can't guess what he was thinking.
He was irrational.
l ordered him placed far
from the fighting, but...
he plunged in against my wishes.
He forgives me for all
that he knew l would do.
But can l forgive myself?
Forgive?
l loved him.
l love him still.
Still.
And in pretending to love
you, l do something awful.
You pretend.
l have sinned against love and
God for the sake of your mercy...
which you would not have
given without my sin.
l will burn in hell.
So will you.
No, my love.
You will burn in hell.
l will not.
For l am king...
ordained by God!
Come on! We have no time!
- Here! My bag!
- Where are you going?
There's still much to be done.
l'll be gone for a few days.
Make sure everything is
ready when l get back.
You want me to do the
impossible and do it alone?
l offer you the perfect solution-
a revolution without bloodshed...
without loss of life,
even without treason.
For he, too, is a king's son. Thank you.
But l can't get him ready.
We'll never have time.
The urgency is not my choice.
lnstead of distributing
the promised food...
Louis has ordered that
all rioters be shot.
Go on. Can you imagine
what will happen...
when the starving people of
Paris hear about his new ball?
This is not for me.
This is for everything we
once were and might be again.
Thank you, Father.
The ball has been brought
forward to tomorrow night.
Tomorrow? Why?
The king is unhappy with his mistress
and seeks revelry to lift his spirits.
l cannot be ready unless
my tailors work all night.
Saddle my horse!
The brothel is closed for the night!
Everybody, out, except the ladies!
Out!
- Closed? We came here-
- Go somewhere else tonight! Out!
Ladies, l need you to finish
my clothes you're making for me.
We'll go and we'll take
your money with you.
Come on, old man. Quickly!
You try to rob me
because you think me old?
Let's see if you rob somebody
with you pistol up there!
Out! Everybody, out!
l finished this for you.
l love Paris. l love life.
And l love you, ladies.
Now get busy. Except for you.
No, wait.
With a king it is so.
Servants have touched the
goblet of the king, therefore...
he will touch it as little as possible.
Again.
- l'm sorry.
- No.
- l didn't-
- Do not be sorry.
There are no mistakes
when you are the king.
You must never apologize.
The king cares for
nothing and for no one.
ls that the kind of
king you wish me to be?
Or do you say this
because your son is dead?
Forgive me. l would
never mean to disrespect-
l'm not angry with
you. Do you understand?
Good. Of course we wish
you to be a good king.
But first you must pass as Louis.
And Louis is cold and cruel.
The eyes of this king say that
he cares for nothing but himself.
Your eyes ask too much.
You shouldn't care about me.
You mustn't ask about my son.
Bless me, Father, for l have sinned.
And so have l.
Your Majesty.
l have come to ask you
whether you believe that...
just as one lie can destroy a life...
so one truth can put it together again.
l have prayed every
day for such a miracle.
l have prayed every day for forgiveness.
But now l know that forgiveness
must first come from you...
before it can come from God.
For it was l who took the second
of your twin sons away from you.
And l was never brave enough...
to find the truth when l was
told one lie after another.
l have raised a son
who destroys lives...
instead of saving them.
And l have failed...
to save a son who died
within an iron mask.
That mask was the creation of Louis.
Now God and we...
have the chance to make a miracle
to strip all masks away forever.
These rooms are yours.
Through this corridor
and up the stairway...
or through this secret
passageway to the floor above...
are the rooms of your
mistress, Christine.
And whose rooms are these?
Your mother's.
My mother's?
Change the horses!
Clear out everything!
Now!
Remember, Philippe, nobility
is born in the heart.
Make love as if you don't care.
And fart whenever you wish.
Hold your goblet with two fingers. All
you have to do is get through tonight.
Smile and nod a lot. lf you get stuck...
just wave and announce, ''Continue.''
ln the morning, order that
Athos, Porthos and Aramis...
be brought to the
palace as your advisors.
And all will be well.
D'Artagnan watches everything.
We have to be lucky.
We make our own luck
tonight, if Philippe holds up.
Relax, Philippe, you're doing well.
My brother.
What is wrong, Your Majesty?
Nothing. Carry on.
Did you see that?
- See what, Your Majesty?
- A mask. l distinctly saw a mask.
Well, the ballroom is full
of masks, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
Carry on, everyone.
ls he all right?
To the passageway.
Your Majesty.
lt's judgement day.
Don't look so shocked, Philippe.
Why do you call me Philippe?
We have a prison for you.
D'Artagnan guards the hallway.
You must go back the way we came.
Time to go, Your Majesty.
You know the way.
You have the heart of a king.
Continue.
Your Majesty.
Some refreshments, Your Majesty?
The Queen Mother!
God bless the king and the Queen Mother!
l'll retire now.
Wait two dances...
then withdraw to your room...
and spend the night in safety.
We have much to talk about...
and have the rest of our lives to do it.
Good night...
Mother.
my son.
Anne. What-
Tomorrow.
How long has the king been back?
Some while, Captain.
Murderer!
l wrote to the front under your seal.
l wrote as you...
demanding to know why the
general disregarded the order...
to keep Raoul out of danger.
He writes back...
''But, Your Majesty...
your last letter ordered me to place
him at the vanguard of the assault...
just in front of the cannon.''
You killed Raoul!
Stop! You're hurting her!
However l have wronged
you, l will make amends.
Take her to her room.
Deploy the Musketeers.
Guard all the passages.
Continue.
We have an emergency of
security, Your Majesty.
l must ask you to accompany me.
Not now.
The ball. My guests.
l insist, Your Majesty.
Yes, certainly.
They've raised the alarm!
- They'll try to cut us off.
- Reverse the flow!
l am Porthos!
And l fight the king!
Come on! Porthos!
Everyone, pump!
Stop them before they reach the river!
Pull them back!
This man is an impostor.
This is the impostor.
Pull them back!
Get in the boat, Your Majesty.
Open the gate.
l failed you.
We failed you.
Stop!
You take my king, and
l shall take yours.
Catch him! Seize him!
Hold him!
l was told this impostor was dead.
You knew?
You knew there was a
man of such resemblance?
He is my brother.
- Brother?
- My twin.
My blood.
A fact which has kept
him alive, until now.
Please.
- You were a part of this?
- He's your brother! l love you both!
Your love has meant
nothing to either of us!
lt has meant something to me.
Your Majesty, listen to me.
Never once have l asked
anything for myself.
l ask you now: Spare
the life of this man...
this prisoner, your brother.
You have no right to ask me this!
Your Majesty...
every day of your life...
l have watched over you.
l have bled for you.
l have prayed every day to see you
become greater than your office...
better than the law.
Please show me what my faith and
my blood have purchased. Show mercy.
And you take the side of traitors.
Of this one, worst of all,
who's tried to do this to me!
And what have you done to him?
For one moment...
l thought you had become the
king l always hoped you'd be.
Please.
My lord, may l speak?
l beg that you kill me.
l release you from any
sin in taking my life.
ln fact, l pray that God reward
you for your mercy to do it.
But please...
do not, l beg you...
return me to the prison where
l have lived for so long.
You will hunt down Porthos...
Athos and Aramis and
bring me their heads...
or l will have yours.
And as for you, my brother...
back to the prison you shall go...
and into the mask you hate.
Wear it until you love it!
And die in it.
There were two?
Not one, but two?
l couldn't tell you.
You had enough to bear.
l have loved you always.
None but you.
No matter what happens...
l pray you remember that.
Christine's room.
Where is she?
Get rid of it.
Where are you taking me?
Please, no!
lt has been done as you
ordered, Your Majesty.
When D'Artagnan returns, watch him.
And when he leaves again, you tell me.
Your Majesty.
- Nothing down here, sir.
- Try this way.
Philippe has been moved to the
lower dungeon of the Bastille.
At midnight, l will
order the guard changed...
and will delay the
replacements for ten minutes.
One for all. All for one.
lt is a trap, but we have no choice.
lf Philippe is in the Bastille...
then to the Bastille we will go.
l'd rather die covered in blood...
than an old man lying in my own piss.
Our old uniforms.
From our days of glory.
l was saving them so that...
we could wear them in death.
And so we shall!
Open up. We have a prisoner.
Take him down to level three. The
captain will see to the document.
lt worked.
lt's a prison. Of course
it's no trouble getting in.
The problems will come
when we want to get out.
lt's midnight. We have ten minutes.
Down there.
ls this what you're looking for?
The key.
Remember this?
Don't look so sad. There's
nothing left of him anyway.
He was just a snivelling, drooling-
l knew you'd come.
We feared the mask would destroy you.
l wear the mask; it does not wear me.
- The courtyard is blocked.
- He lies.
He's here to trap us.
See for yourselves.
All that you have suffered...
l would gladly have borne
myself to keep it from you.
You men, to the east gate.
D'Artagnan is right. The
courtyard is filling with soldiers.
This way.
Don't stop till you reach the river.
lf we go this way,
they'll know you helped us.
That doesn't matter now. Go.
Fire!
Get that door!
Trapped.
Charge them!
Spare their lives, if you can.
Cowards! Twenty men run from four?
The corridor nullifies our number.
No one wants to fight the captain.
Charge!
l am not angry with you. l knew you
would lead me to them, and so you have.
Lay down your sword and
l will not punish you.
l will let you retire in peace.
And l will give your
friends a swift execution...
if you surrender now.
Perhaps you should take his offer.
We're dead anyway.
He's right.
Wait.
Bargain me to Louis for all your lives.
You've done your best.
Please, let me go.
l cannot do it.
Even if l could give up my king...
l could never give up...
my son.
Your son?
l loved your mother.
l love her still.
You are my son.
l never knew you existed.
And l never...
felt pride as a father...
until this moment.
They're young Musketeers.
They've been weaned on our legends.
They revere us.
lt is an advantage.
Yes. Why don't we charge them?
l trained these men.
They will fight to the death.
But if we must die-
lf we must die...
let it be like this.
One for all. All for one.
Shoot.
Magnificent valor.
Shoot them.
Fire!
Get off me!
He is your brother.
Brother?
Outside. All of you.
You're sworn to silence.
Get this off me.
Forgive me.
All my life-
This-
This is the death...
l have always wanted.
All for one.
One for-
You were the one in the mask.
All my life...
all l ever wanted to be...
was him.
We have recaptured the prisoner.
No, l am the-
You will put this madman where
no one can hear his insanity.
Let him be fed by a deaf mute...
but feed him well.
And let him find redemption in wearing
the pains he has placed on others.
Take him.
And them?
They are my royal council
and truest friends.
He was the best of us all.
After all you have done, l
must ask you one more service.
Let me love you like a son to a father.
And, l pray you, live for this:
To love me like your son.
Musketeers!
Salute!
One for all. All for one.
The prisoner in the iron
mask was never found.
lt was whispered among his jailers
that he received a royal pardon...
and was taken to the country
where he lived quietly...
visited often by the queen.
The king known as Louis XlV...
brought his people food,
prosperity and peace...
and is remembered as
the greatest ruler...
in the history of his nation.