For we meet in an hour
of change and challenge,
in a decade of hope and fear,
in an age of both
knowledge and ignorance.
The greater our knowledge increases,
the greater our ignorance unfolds.
So it is not surprising
that some would have us stay
where we are a little longer.
To rest, to wait.
But this city of Houston,
this state of Texas,
this country of
the United States
was not built by those
who waited and rested
and wished to look behind them.
We choose to go to the moon.
We choose to go to the moon in this
decade and do the other things,
not because they are easy,
but because they are hard.
With this one speech, John f.
Kennedy escalated our cold war
with the Soviet union
to outer space.
Now, if we do not land a man
on the moon by 1969,
we will have broken
JFK's promise.
And in the eyes of the world, the
Soviet union will win the cold war.
To make matters
even more difficult,
the CIA has discovered a leak
coming out of the space program.
Top secret American research is
showing up in Soviet briefings,
which means the KGB has
implanted a mole inside NASA.
If the Russians are able to steal our
technology, they could beat us to the moon.
Just as they beat us into space
with the sputnik satellite in 1957.
The director of NASA, James Webb,
denies the presence of this mole,
which means the CIA must
move in a team undercover.
That's where we come in.
Allow me to introduce
Owen Williams,
and myself, Matt Johnson.
We joined the CIA through
the bright recruits program
and have been working
together ever since.
Along with our camera team, we
make up the CIA's av department.
Currently, we are finishing
operation deep red.
The probe into film director
Stanley Kubrick.
But this mission is not using
us to our full potential.
We are asking to be transferred
off of operation deep red,
and on to operation zipper.
The mission into NASA
to find the mole.
Because of our filmmaking
background, we would make...
Okay, stop.
Stop.
What is this supposed to be?
Okay. It's a...
It's a pitch film.
It... so... it's for operation zipper.
I think...
Operation zipper's already
been assigned.
We know it has.
I think the agency is
making a mistake
with sending
a scientist into NASA.
Well, your opinion
means nothing.
Yeah, okay.
Just... just...
If you watch the rest of this film,
you'll see... I've seen enough.
But we have an amazing plan for
finding the spy. I'm sure you do.
Boles, we worked hard on this. You're seriously
not going to watch the rest of this?
No. Can we show it to Brackett?
No.
Okay.
This was a long shot.
We've only been here
for one year.
We'll get on missions
like this in the future.
I thought this was
going to work.
You knew that it wasn't a great chance.
Yeah, you should...
Jared, you should have cut when
you saw it wasn't going good.
You're supposed to be
filming so that...
I didn't even notice.
Yeah.
Hey.
Okay, I got an idea.
We need to send someone who will look
like they have no idea what's going on.
Us, as a documentary film crew.
We can pretend we are from the national
education... Okay, we have to go.
We got to go.
Is this a good idea?
Andy? It's a good... Hey.
It's a good idea.
Are you ready?
What if they fire us?
What's your first line?
Oh, uh, your plan is to send...
Okay, I'm fine.
Okay. Let's go.
Everyone here?
Boles...
Carry on.
Thank you.
Good morning, everyone.
Hello, my name is special agent Matt
Johnson, and what you're about to watch
is a film detailing the connections
between Stanley Kubrick
and the film Dr. Strangelove or how I
learned to stop worrying and love the bomb.
Conclusion,
Stanley Kubrick is not a spy.
Thank you.
Are there any questions?
That covers it.
Uh, what's next?
Actually, director Brackett,
I'd like to make a pitch for
major research to be moved
onto operation zipper next.
What the hell are you doing?
You guys are trying to put a...
Field agent inside NASA
posing as a scientist, and...
Agent Williams and I
don't think it will work.
This mole, if he's there,
could have been at NASA
since the early 60s.
He's going to spot one of our guys pretending
to be a rocket scientist instantly.
We need to send people
who are going to look like they
have no idea what's going on.
Us.
As a documentary film crew.
We can pretend that we're from the
national education television network,
filming the definitive
Apollo documentary.
We're there to chart the race to the moon.
Smart idea.
But no Soviet mole's gonna
let anyone openly film 'em.
Well, director Brackett, we're filming
you right now through the window.
You're going to have to buy
us better cameras, though.
Jesus Christ.
Okay, here we go.
Let's hope they buy this.
Ready?
Whoa!
- Hi!
Just let us get our stuff.
Yeah, yeah!
You need help, Andy?
Do you mind if we film this?
Yeah, why not.
Here, at the end
of the hall on the right...
Oh, man.
That's mission control?
Yeah, actually. We'll have
to get in there later.
Hmm.
Hi.
We're a documentary film crew.
Jared, make sure you're getting
this crisp and in focus,
I don't want to have to edit
together out of focus stuff, please.
- Sorry.
- No problem.
Your office is just right here.
Okay, here you go.
Wow!
You guys don't need
anything else?
No, uh, we'll come find you if we do.
We'll just get set up.
Thanks, Sharon.
Bye!
She bought it. We're a
documentary film crew.
You see how they look at us? See
how they look in the cameras?
Yeah.
This is the best mission I've
ever been on in my life.
This is, uh...
This is Matt.
Mike.
Nice to meet you.
And, uh, this is Jared.
They're filming a documentary about
the, uh... The Apollo mission.
Oh, okay!
So, we basically are asking
about what you do, and... Sure!
And... and I'm ready.
Yeah. Okay.
Well, I work here
in the public affairs office,
and one of my duties is
the media products,
specifically still photos.
And I stood up in the theater
in sugar land and I said,
"don't eat those meatballs!
He did not wash his hands."
I had to...
I appreciate your time. Before we launch
to the moon, come back and see us, okay?
I will.
Okay.
Thanks, guys. That's a wrap.
We got it.
All right, and mark it.
- Milt interview.
- Take one.
Thanks, Owen.
So, I guess you can start
just by telling us your name.
Milt Heflin.
And what is it you do
here at NASA?
Huh. Uh...
Okay.
Shut the door.
Guys, can we get a shot of
just the lounge being busy?
I know you're all working,
but if you want to just...
Busy, like there's
some activity.
Or, do whatever feels natural.
And action.
No, don't look at the cameras. Just
keep sitting. Just keep standing there.
Part of Sato's controversial
south-east Asia...
the north Vietnamese
decides to accept us offers...
spread over 600 feet to
become a gigantic pool of flames
a fire extinguisher called purple k,
three tragic fires aboard aircraft...
One second, Mr. Webb.
We're good?
Mr. Webb, tell me,
what does it mean
when people say the Russians are
ahead of us in the space race?
Well, I think it means
that the job of
landing something on the moon
where there's no atmosphere,
and using a rocket
to slow it up,
and having the equipment
still work
is a very difficult job.
Uh, I think it means the Russians
are trying, just like we are...
Where's this guy's office?
But I think the real
meaning is...
Two more pieces.
- Come on, Jared.
- Got it, got it!
Okay, hold on.
I'm fine, I need light.
Ready?
Test, test, test, test...
then you get to talk about
how to go forward. To do it.
Uh, I am not much interested,
and I don't think it's very realistic to
talk about technological interchange,
and this kind of thing. You
first gotta get on the basis
where... where...
Okay, so...
His phone rings, in his office,
and this phone rings
at the same time.
As long as we're rolling
when he picks up,
we get everything.
I found us a house.
It's beautiful, it's red,
it has a nursery and a yard.
You'll love it.
How big is the bed?
It's a queen.
Are you alone right now?
No, I'm at work.
What are you doing?
Do you want to know
what I'm wearing?
Julie, I can't do this right now.
I'm at the office.
I'm sorry, maybe later.
Well, I'm wearing a pink bra and
that black skirt you bought me.
Honey, Matt is right beside me and
I'm at work. Can I call you tonight?
I'm taking off the skirt now.
There's nothing underneath.
Whoa!
What are you doing?
Nothing.
I'm trying to have fun with you.
Wait a second, hold on... No!
What is it?
We're not doing anything.
I'm doing work.
Hello?
Don't do that.
What'd you find in that phone?
What? What?
Oh, my god.
We've been bugged.
We've been bugged, guys.
No, no, no!
Anything else,
or is that it? Owen?
That's it from this car?
Guys?
I said I was sorry!
Your hat?
- A couple more boxes here.
- These are not a big deal.
Please don't touch me.
I'll get the rest!
We both, uh, have had and
will have emergencies,
and, uh, that each flight, uh, has
some element of extreme risk,
and some elements of...
I made this statement on
my own, from my knowledge,
uh, longstanding knowledge...
setting us back four years...
Well...
Uh...
300 second burn
to the lunar surface...
This is nothing.
Give it a second. 250
seconds is all we can do?
That's the maximum.
- And you know that...
- Did you talk to TRW?
- Who's the other voice?
- I dunno.
Their fuels.
Grumman has fucked us.
They built a lander
that can't land.
So, we are going back...
With whom?
This is setting us
back four years.
Well, I agree. This is
going to have to change.
Change? We can't
land on the moon.
Unless by some miracle
Braun finds lighter fuel,
we aren't touching down
for five years.
Okay... We're just going to
be circling forever up there.
So what are we telling everyone?
- Nothing.
- We don't tell anyone...
Do you understand
what this means?
NASA can't do it.
They can't land man
and come back.
Have you called Brackett?
Of course not! I needed
to tell you guys first.
We have to tell Brackett. We have
to tell Brackett right away.
This is something you report right away.
We need help.
We have to...
Relax, it's okay. Yes. Yes.
And we need... I'll tell
you what to do, okay?
I'm gonna tell you what to do.
Find out who that other guy on
the phone was, okay?
Because, if we found
this out in a month,
you better fucking believe that
the mole can do the same thing.
And now all of a sudden the Russians
know we can't make it to the moon,
then what the fuck are
we going to do?
Okay. Okay. Okay.
You call Langley.
It's ringing.
You think I'll get to talk
to the president? No.
That's not unrealistic.
I could. He could be like, "we need
to get this right to the president."
I'll be like, "all right.
"Give me his
home phone, sir. I'll..."
Hello?
Director Brackett, it's agent
Johnson calling from Houston.
We have big news.
What's that?
They can't make it to the moon.
We intercepted a call
from Jim Webb.
From what I understand,
they can circle the moon,
but they can't actually land.
They... they don't have
the technology to do it.
They're saying 1971
at the earliest.
Damn it.
Give me a minute.
Okay, who else knows about this?
Uh, nobody, from...
From...
From what we can tell.
They're talking about it
on the phone
like it was a big secret. Like they've
never talked about it before.
Okay, good.
Another unit is going
to take over zipper.
Get your team out of there.
Uh... you think maybe
that's a bit, uh,
shortsighted in a way?
Seeing as we're here undercover now?
What... why?
Don't question my orders, kid.
I'm not... I don't mean
to question it. I...
I just... I simply think
that we're here
and I... We have to figure
out a response to this,
somehow, and you've got us...
We're going home.
If either of us are talking, shoot. I
don't care how much film you burn,
it doesn't matter.
Okay? It's going to save us.
What are we doing in here?
Sit down, just listen
to this, okay?
Well...
Hold on a sec... Did you
call Brackett last night?
Yes, all right?
What did he say?
Okay, turn this on.
What did they say?
I'm gonna tell you
what they said.
Okay, it's on.
Okay, you hear that?
Yeah.
- You recognize it?
- Yeah.
It's sputnik.
You know what?
You're ahead of me.
Okay, yeah.
It's sputnik.
How do you know it's sputnik?
Can you... did you
sleep here last night?
That's not plugged
into anything.
It's... it's just a dial on the other side.
It's not actually sputnik.
It's just making
you think that it is.
It's just a random beeping.
And because you think that
that's supposed to be sputnik,
that's why you believe
it's sputnik.
This is what we are
going to do with the moon.
I called Brackett,
told him that they
can't make it for '69.
He said, "okay, well, you've got
to figure out a way to fix it."
And I said, "we can
do it on our own.
"We can make a film that
shows us going to the moon
"without actually doing it."
We know that
they can make it up there.
We're not... we're faking
the last little piece.
The tiny... The tiny
thing they can't do.
Land and come back.
The thing JFK said we'd do.
That's the only part.
Everything else is real,
do you understand?
Yeah, I understand
what you're saying.
And I understand
that it sounds like...
Read this, it's from Brackett.
He sent a briefing?
Yes.
If we can pull this off,
we are going to look
like geniuses.
Four guys inside of NASA
figure out how to
make it look like we went to the moon.
We did it.
That's crazy!
This is exactly what
we've been waiting for.
It literally fell on our lap.
We could run our own department
after something like this.
Is there
more information coming?
About what?
Well, the objectives
and the budget.
Why?
This doesn't seem
incomplete to you?
Incomplete? How?
What do you mean?
Well, I...
Okay...
You know what, don't...
Don't worry about this.
They obviously told us exactly
what they want us to hear,
so our job is to film a
test, and that's it.
Come on.
Does it... you don't have an
ethical problem with this at all?
In what way?
In that this is lying.
You know what, this is like
one of those good lies.
Like Santa Claus
and the Easter bunny.
A lot of kids get really
mad about those.
So we're shooting this
at 48 frames a second,
so you're going to
have to move like...
Like you're being lifted up...
Okay? Like this... This thing
weighs about 100 pounds.
Well, just try it.
Try leaping a bit.
Like this.
Yeah, good.
Go! Action! Action!
More that way.
More towards me a bit.
Walk off that way.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Stop.
We should be
doing this at night.
Can, can the light move a
little bit to the left?
I'm being devoured
and I'm cookin'.
No, that's too far.
That's too far.
Back over this way.
Back to your right.
It doesn't matter...
Stop! Stop!
Okay, now a bit to your left.
How much does
the light drop off?
Are you not getting
destroyed by mosquitoes?
Okay, I am, but I'm trying
to get this right. Hold on.
What else is in the frame?
Uh, I see some logs
in the background.
Yeah, I see it, too.
Okay, I'm getting it.
That's what you're...
Please, let's just roll.
It's fine, it's fine.
It's not a log, it's a rock!
It's okay, we'll frame it out.
I'm going to use it!
I'm going to put it
in the frame.
Are you ready?
And action!
Owen, jump in the air.
Holy shit.
It's open!
Hey.
You're just in time.
Have a seat. So...
The moon footage...
I won't say how it looks.
I just want you to watch it, okay?
Turn the lights off.
So it may seem a bit different.
I think you'll enjoy it.
This is the year
before we got recruited.
Wow.
Who is it?
Hello?
Director Brackett,
this is a... uh, come on in.
Welcome.
It's great to see you guys.
This is a surprise.
What the hell is going on?
You're changing the direction on this
project without my authorization?
Okay...
Shut up. I'm not finished.
Okay, now listen...
I'm shutting this operation...
Wait!
Bring it down. It's over.
You made this up?
Okay, yes.
I made up a mission.
But that's because I wanted to make sure
it would work before I brought it to you.
I think I may have solved
the moon problem.
Just... trust me.
Watch this.
Sorry.
Ignore this. Ignore this.
So that's just sand.
William's in the suit.
We shot it in slow motion.
You understand?
I'm saying we could fake the moon
landing, and it wouldn't be hard.
All people want to see
is an image
on a television screen
and we can give them that.
The rocket will go up,
we'll send our
footage with them,
and the astronauts will
just beam it back to earth.
No one is going to think this is fake,
because how insane would that be?
And if we do it right,
this is the kind of thing
that sells itself.
Walter Cronkite is going
to do half the work for us.
Let me try.
Give us a minute.
It's okay.
Hi.
Whoa!
Okay, just shoot
from down there, okay?
Owen?
Put... put your mic on.
No.
Put your mic on. Put your... It'll
take two seconds. Put your mic on.
Come on. It'll take two seconds.
I'm not doing this, okay?
Get the fuck off.
Cheer up!
We just got a huge
promotion, come on!
Whoo!
Mr. boles, I guess we'll
be working together again.
Welcome to Texas.
Congratulations on having Brackett
approve this insane mission.
You guys are filming
this right now?
Yeah, we film everything.
It's a documentary.
It's a documentary film.
Okay, before we get started on this,
I know you're technically my boss,
but I'm running all this.
Yeah.
No, I'm here because you have
no idea what you're doing.
So I'm in charge and you
don't run a goddamn thing.
So no more fucking around
behind our backs, all right?
Wow, I heard it's pretty shitty.
Hi.
How you doing?
Enjoying the 4th of July?
Yes, I'm in a great mood.
This is a bit of a party for me,
too, because we got a promotion.
Did you?
Yeah.
Somebody just
tell me what's wrong.
Is that...
That's the barbecue.
The barbecue what? What happened
at the barbecue? What's going on?
Watch.
Right...
There. See that?
Yeah, two guys.
Yeah. Look at this.
So he's holding something,
we're thinking maybe super 8.
It could be a 35mm still camera.
And do we know who this is?
Maybe they're NASA guests.
Yeah, I don't know.
Tourists? Who knows, right?
It could be nothing.
It is nothing...
Who is it?
It's boles.
This looks like shit.
You have one guy
in a space suit,
prancing around on the sand...
with one rock.
Who do you think
this is gonna convince?
I...
It convinced Brackett.
Well, now you have
to convince me.
What are you talking about?
Nobody is going to buy this.
I thought you were advocating
for me to do this!
I was advocating
for operation Northwoods.
I think this idea's ridiculous.
Mike, do you remember
mentioning, uh, test locations
that NASA was using
for photography?
Would you mind
showing me those pictures?
You mean on camera, or...
If you don't mind.
I don't mind.
These are places that look
like the moon on earth?
Exactly. These are called
geology field trips.
So you're saying that the
rocks that are on the moon
are the exact same
as the rocks on earth?
I'm not saying exact. I'm saying...
But they're close?
They're close enough that...
That...
Yeah, I mean... So if you saw
them, you would think that, uh...
Oh, yeah, you can
get an igneous rock
from a volcano here in America
and tell somebody
it's a moon rock
and they wouldn't know.
Really?
Yeah.
- Hello.
- Is Owen home?
He's in the garage.
You look great.
FBI!
Look at this!
The geologists have
places on earth
that already look like the moon.
This is the Barringer crater,
the Grand Canyon.
We shoot this test footage
and then compare it
with the real moon footage
that they're getting
from the missions.
I just figured this out!
Yeah, I can't go on this trip.
What?
What do you mean?
Why?
Because I... because I...
I need you.
If you don't come with me I'm
going with boles, by myself.
What? Are you
still mad at me?
I'm sorry.
I didn't...
Owen!
One second!
I... you have to forgive me for this.
Listen.
I can't go.
You're fucking me. You are...
You're fucking me.
This is the big shot.
The ride without astronauts of
the giant Saturn v live rocket.
Project Apollo.
This is Apollo 4.
The test of our moon rocket
in flight for the first time.
It is the beginning,
the first of many steps,
which will someday put men
on the surface of the moon.
How far off can you see?
You've got to picture it
in black and white.
With the sun behind us there.
We can even do a pan.
What do you think?
We don't know if you can hear,
ladies and gentlemen.
But, oh, the flight is moving
along as it should be...
But our tape records are
being thrown to the floor
by the roar of
this mighty rocket,
as it continues
to climb into the sky,
on its seven and a half
million pounds of thrust.
It's a beautiful sight,
an unbelievable sight...
So I didn't tell him
I made the whole thing up,
and then you
and Brackett show up,
and then he punches me,
now he's acting like
we aren't friends.
What would you do?
Well, I wouldn't have done
that in the first place.
Okay, yeah, but pretend
that you're as stupid as me
and you have done that.
God damn it, look at this!
We weren't even close.
No kidding.
Here.
Okay... Okay, who else
has seen this footage?
Everyone.
See, this is what we need.
We need the actual
footage of the moon.
How do we get astronauts
to act in front of this?
You could start
by hiring a real director.
Or you could give up
this mission.
Yeah.
Hey, don, how are you?
It's Matt Johnson.
No, I'm calling from Houston,
they got me out here
on operation zipper.
Listen, can...
I actually need a favor.
Do we have a last known
address for Stanley Kubrick
when we were doing
operation deep red?
I'm looking at some of his
movie effects and...
"No, of course I'd
like to say hello!"
Of course I'd like to say hello.
And I'm watching something.
Would you mind giving me that?
Hi, could you give me the phone
number to an address in New York?
239.
Uh, actually, it's Polaris
productions, incorporated.
23...
My name's Matt Johnson,
I'm a documentary filmmaker
working at NASA,
and I need to ask him
a few questions.
Is he there?
It's an emergency.
Of course not. No. And... And
that's not what this is, ma'am.
Yes, hello, my name is
Michael Kubrick.
I'm looking for my brother.
Well, I'm calling
from the United States
and I'm... and I'm really
trying to talk with him.
I've got some very bad news
about our father.
Can you give me
a phone number for that?
What time is it in England?
I'm looking for
a Mr. Stanley Kubrick.
I'm a documentary filmmaker
from the United States.
This is not a personal call.
I'm actually calling from
NASA and I'm wondering if...
Oh, thank you.
Hello, Madeleine. I'm not sure
why I got connected with you.
I'm calling from NASA.
I'm making a documentary here
about the Apollo program.
Ah.
What are you guys
doing over there,
if you don't mind me asking?
Stanley Kubrick is making a new
movie about the moon landing,
and I'm willing to bet that we
can use the special effects
that he's doing there
to do this.
Okay, but...
We can't just walk
onto a film set.
He has two NASA scientists
advising him.
We're going to go and say
we're going to interview them.
Do you see what's going on here?
Kubrick is getting NASA
to make sure that his space
movie looks like real space.
And so we're going
to use his space movie
to make sure the real space
movie looks like space!
Do you understand
how crazy that is?
Welcome to England!
It's not too loud?
No, well, it'll be
packed inside the bag.
Not bad for... For on the
spot, just figured it out!
Jared, wave!
Jared, big wave!
Yeah, that's her.
Madeleine!
You won't be able to bring
that camera inside.
You'll have to shut it off as
soon as we get in, I'm afraid.
Is Mr...
The set's all live.
No problem.
Is Mr. Kubrick inside?
He is, but security
is very tight.
You'll be thrown off the set if you
try to approach him, so please don't.
You got it.
Go ahead.
Thank you.
Please wait right here.
Yeah, sure.
We'll stay right here.
It might be better to just
play it as a medium shot
- in this situation.
- Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
Can you do it
with your head down?
What about out there?
- Well, that's not bad.
- Let's do that.
Right.
Check the gate, Doug.
I... I would never normally do
this, but it's for a friend.
His name is Matt Johnson.
Mmm-hmm.
Jared, tell me
you are getting this.
Oh, my god.
Excuse me?
How did you set this up?
Owen, it's called
front screen projection!
We got it!
Kubrick's technique,
how he's faking...
I wanna...
I wanna tell you.
Boles, hey.
It's called
front screen projection.
We figured out how to,
how to do it.
Yeah, okay, all right.
I'll, uh...
Do you want us
to fly right there, or...
Sure.
All right, it's called
front screen projection.
Stanley Kubrick can fake
any environment he wants,
by projecting it through
a semi-transparent mirror
and then onto
a gigantic silver screen.
Then he films the entire scene
through the same mirror,
at a 90-degree angle
to the projector.
What it winds up doing
is creating images
where you can't tell
where the stage stops
and the fake photographic
background begins.
You have an infinite
depth of field,
into environments that exist
completely in two-dimensional space.
We can do the same thing with
the lunar surface photography
that NASA is taking
on the Apollo missions.
Movie special effects
can be very convincing,
especially when you don't
know you're watching a movie.
The plan is to rent
a film studio in Texas,
hire a crew, and have them
build our own lunar lander.
We'll mix
this practical set piece,
with Kubrick's projection
technique, and presto,
the illusion that man
is walking on the moon.
Now I know you're probably thinking
this is too much exposure,
and that the risk of bringing
in outsiders is too high,
but we already have
the perfect cover.
We're making a documentary
about the moon landing.
And it's not a stretch to say that we're
building sets to conduct interviews,
shoot b-roll footage.
We could even say
it's for simulations.
Hell, most of the major networks
are doing this already.
The only people who need to
know what's actually happening
are the astronauts,
who you should select based on
their willingness to cooperate,
and James Webb,
who's either going to have to work
with us, or get out of the way.
And that's the easy part.
We also need to convince
everybody at NASA.
The good news is the only people
who are in contact with the rocket
are all in one room in Houston,
inside mission control.
If we can convince
mission control
that what they're doing is real,
everybody else will follow.
How do we do that?
Well, mission control
actually monitors everything,
from the heart rates
of the astronauts,
to the exact location
of the lunar module
as it descends to the moon.
And they're getting all this
information through radio,
directly from the ship.
The good news is that
they've run so many tests
with this exact mission
that they actually have telemetric
data of successful lunar landings,
stored on guidance systems
on Apollo 11.
Here's where we get very lucky.
As the command module
passes along
to the dark side of the moon,
the radio signals
can't penetrate the core.
For 30 minutes, we have a window
for the astronauts to switch from
real data, to fake telemetric data.
Mission control
will be getting data
of the lunar module undocking and
landing on the lunar surface,
but it will be completely faked.
Combine that with our footage
that the astronauts are going to pipe
into the broadcast back to earth,
and nobody's
going to have any idea.
As far as NASA and the rest
of the world is concerned,
the United States
just landed on the moon.
Finally, the broadcast.
To shoot in slow motion,
we have to shoot film.
To broadcast
it needs to be video.
Which means we have
to do a transfer,
which normally would be fine,
except that people cannot know
it originally began as film.
That means a single
scratch, any dust...
Okay, okay.
We got it.
Thank you for the presentation.
You can go ahead.
- Thank you, sir.
- Talk to your folks about the Northwoods plan.
Tell them to put a hold on it
and we'll see how this develops.
Director, what is
the Northwoods plan?
I've never heard of
operation Northwoods.
Shoot down Apollo 11
and blame the Soviets.
With the astronauts
on the flight?
Why would we do that?
If your film
doesn't come together,
then we have to have
a backup plan.
And that is our backup plan.
Plan? I've never heard
of operation Northwoods.
Shoot down Apollo 11
and blame the Soviets.
Who were these men
going to the moon?
David Schoumacher profiled
the crew of Apollo 11.
Neil Armstrong,
the man chosen to be first
to step upon the moon.
He is by all accounts
intelligent, courteous,
sober, a good family man.
He is perfect for the role,
beyond what a Hollywood
scriptwriter would dare.
Buzz Aldrin is perhaps the most
brilliant of the astronauts.
Some say even a genius.
His doctorate at Mit came after
a thesis on orbital rendezvous,
and he understands the abstract
theory of space mechanics
as well as anyone.
Mike Collins is the least technical in
outlook of the Apollo 11 astronauts,
but the most philosophical.
If he does not love machines,
he does love wine,
and books, and roses.
A man who has known all
three pilots for many years
says if he were
forced down on an island,
he would want it
to be with Collins
for the quality
of his personality.
Another said
he would prefer Aldrin,
because with his intelligence
he would soon be converting
sea water to fresh water
and otherwise logically
attacking the problem.
But both agreed
in the final analysis,
that they would hope
it was with Armstrong,
because, somehow,
he would get them off of it.
Hello?
Boles, we just got back.
Where are you?
Okay. Turn on the TV.
Yeah, okay.
I'm turning it on now.
- Why?
- Summarize what you just said,
and then we'll ask you some questions
about seeing the president?
Uh, yes, I'd like to say
that, uh, over a year ago,
president Johnson and I
reviewed the space program
and, uh, agreed
to build strength
so that I might retire
on my 62nd birthday,
which happens to be
this next October 7th.
Today, we have reviewed
the progress we have made
and the president has agreed
that I could retire
on October 7th,
when I will be 62.
I'd like to say
one other thing...
Yeah, okay.
Well, I guess that means
he didn't want
to cooperate, huh?
Okay, yeah.
I'll see you when you get back.
Bye.
Andy!
Sorry.
What are you doing? Shooting
for the documentary.
Oh, okay, fine.
Where's Owen?
He's at the hospital.
What?
Julie had the baby.
Oh, shit!
Hey.
I missed it, hey?
Hey, mom.
Wow!
Matt!
What's his name?
Simon.
Can I hold him?
Sure, if you want to.
I need to talk to you.
I need to talk to Matt.
Okay. What's up?
One minute.
Okay, okay.
What the hell is this?
Jared showed me
the photos of the men
who were watching us
at the barbecue.
They're filming us, Matt! Okay.
Why are you bringing
this up at the hospital?
Relax!
Relax? This could
be the Russians.
We have to get off this mission.
If we get caught, the CIA
will abandon us, okay?
I'm calling Brackett to them him...
No! No! No!
You are not calling Brackett.
No one's calling Brackett.
You are being paranoid!
I hope so, because if I'm
right and this is the mole...
If they find out
what we are doing,
then we are fucking dead.
You got that?
Looks pretty good.
"Looks pretty good"?
Guys, come on.
Are you kidding me?
All right.
This cost $45,000!
Really?
Yeah!
Oh, god, don't start that.
"Really? Hey,
you got ripped off.
"Hey, come on, I could have
done this..." ...Cheaper.
"With $20
and some elbow grease!"
Do you think it would kill you
to say, "good job, Matt"?
I mean that seriously. Do you think
it would physically kill you?
Okay, and it's for a film shoot.
Uh, we're making a documentary
about the moon landing,
and we need to make
a lunar surface.
And so it's like a fake lunar surface.
That's what we need.
So I don't know how much
sand you can ship us.
But, uh, four tons?
How many tons are in a truck?
Can you hold on a sec?
Where are you going?
Uh, sorry, say again?
Actually, I went to a place in
Arizona called cinder lake,
where the sand was brown as molasses.
It was beautiful.
It was a beautiful brown.
Molten brown.
So, what are these guys gonna
say when they're up here?
We need something they
can print as a headline.
Type out a couple things and let's
just see what we got, okay?
So try this,
"welcome to the moon."
Catch!
So, no, leave that where
it was, it's my a rock.
I think if we never say
the word "America."
Oh, yeah, we just take
an American symbol.
Exactly. Eagle.
- Freedom.
- Frontier.
Frontier.
So that needs to make
that pothole there.
Does that have a label on it?
B. So that goes right at your feet.
Perfect.
I just got an idea.
You know what we've gotta have
them do when they're up there?
Who is it, Galileo
or somebody, said...
Oh, drop the feather.
Drop the feather and the hammer.
And he said, in a vacuum,
a hammer and a feather
would fall at the same speed.
Well, okay, but how are
we gonna do that?
A lead feather.
Wait a minute, we gotta keep the
flag as stable as possible,
because the wind resistance
makes it billow.
You wave the flag.
You can't do that!
Okay Houston, I'm about
to step off the LM.
He leaves a footprint there.
'Cause they would leave
footprints there. Exactly!
And we so can send photographs
of that back home.
It's... that's...
That is the image!
Write that down, the footprints!
The word "foot" is disgusting.
Maybe people
don't want to hear "foot."
No, "with this step." You
would say, "with this step."
"With this step."
Okay, okay.
"With this step, I..."
No. "As man walks
on the moon..."
Too literal.
Too literal!
"The step of
a single man..."
"The step of a single man.
"But for us
back at home..."
Think of what
a step is like to us.
To a man, a step is just a step.
But to an ant looking up at
the man, he looks like a god.
And it doesn't look like a step,
it looks like a towering leap.
It's like a leap.
It's like a jump.
And this is a leap forward for...
For everything!
The next evolutionary step.
A leap forward in science.
- For humanity.
- Exactly!
This is good.
Okay, let's try one.
Hey.
Do you know who that is outside?
Who?
Right there.
Look.
Where?
Tell me whose that is.
Is he running?
Did you say hi? Did he look
at you when you came in?
Is there even a guy in there?
He's sitting there watching.
Shh. Shh. Go
outside, you'll see.
I'm sure he works for the studio.
I'll go talk to him.
They know we're here. We're
allowed to be here, okay?
Relax.
Okay.
Hi.
Go, go, go, go!
Jared, get in the car!
Boles, what are you doing?
What happened?
You shot your fucking gun!
Jared, shoot out the front,
try to get their license plate!
Come on!
- No!
- What?
What happened?
What happened to your car?
It stalled.
They got away.
Well, did
you get a look at them?
Whoever it is,
they know we're here.
Well, we don't know who it is.
I think it's the mole.
I think it's the mole that you guys sent
us here to find in the first place.
Who else is waiting
outside the studio
and then the minute we walk out...
Let's lock it up.
Let's lock it up
and call Brackett.
What... lock it up?
We're in the middle of this!
We can't just stop shooting!
Well, there might be
guys on the roof.
What do you mean,
guys on the roof?
What the fuck is going on?
And what, you got a gun?
This is CBS news special report.
The flight of Apollo 8.
Six days to the moon and back.
Brought to you
by Walter Cronkite.
The flight of Apollo 8 is over.
And all that remains is to remove the
astronauts from the space craft,
and carry them
less than two miles
to the deck of
the carrier Yorktown.
Future plans for space
missions, of course,
have been accelerated
considerably.
It means that they
can keep to the hoped-for
schedule of the next
Apollo 9 mission,
late in February,
or early in march,
to test out the landing module,
and, uh, then move on towards
landing a man on the moon
two flights further on
in the middle of July.
So we've got
good news and bad news.
Good news, his name
is Antonin Lhotsky.
Uh-huh.
- He's a KGB agent.
He's the man from outside
the studio the other night.
Whoa, what?
We suspect he's been the
mole the entire time.
So... so then he knows about avalanche.
We're fucked!
We don't think he does.
We've been interrogating him
for the past couple of days.
He doesn't seem
to know anything.
We've raided
his house. Nothing.
This guy's the mole?
And you... you got him?
We got him.
So, then what?
We're just...
We're good?
Well, not entirely.
We, uh, got some new intel
on the Soviet progress,
and it turns out they're doing
better than we thought.
It looks like they could possibly make
it to the moon by the end of '69.
Which means that we need to be
done by April at the latest.
Yeah, that puts us
on a pretty tight timeline.
They know we're here.
We're allowed to be here, okay?
Relax.
Hi.
Go, go, go, go!
Jared, get in the car!
Hello?
Matt, we have a problem here.
Gentleman got the contract
with, I don't know, somebody.
This is who they say
the mole was.
So we interviewed him?
Yeah, over a year ago.
Remember when you asked me to find
out who was on the phone with Webb?
Of course.
I did.
Second burn
to the lunar surface.
Then we can go in after...
For 250.
250 seconds is all we can do?
That's the maximum,
and you know that...
Did you talk to TRW?
Yeah. And you know how they
are about their fuels.
So we are in trouble...
Grumman...
What does this mean?
So the mole knew that we
couldn't make it to the moon
for over a year?
I don't think so.
I don't think
that Lhotsky's the mole,
I don't think Lhotsky
was outside the studio.
I mean, Lhotsky knows that we
can't make it to the moon,
so maybe they...
He wouldn't cooperate
and they had to
make him a fall guy
by saying that he's the mole.
They?
Yeah.
What do you mean? The CIA.
Okay, well then, who's outside
the studio following us?
CIA agents.
That's why boles
didn't shoot them.
They're all working together.
They're all watching us,
and they're lying to us.
For what?
For what purpose?
They know everything
that we're doing.
Why... This doesn't
make any sense.
There's no reason
for them to be following us.
You... have you...
Have you heard of a
conspiracy theory before?
Yeah.
I think we're in one.
Okay, leg out!
That doesn't look real.
Okay, you know what we'll do?
Jump on the count of three.
Ready?
I'm bringing the bounce in.
That's a big jump.
Come on, you're supposed
to be Neil Armstrong.
He's brave. Ready?
There we go.
Uh, change the background.
One more.
How about that?
Great.
That's great.
What are we getting in the
reflection of his helmet?
Am I in it?
We'll have
to replace that after.
That looks great.
And then you just...
We have to repress this.
Put that on an animation
stand and reshoot it.
This is the original
from the sound stage.
And the crater textures
are added after.
Getting rid of the
details in the studio.
You go in and you black out
the areas with litho ink.
Let's move this
a little bit further down,
because it seems
a little too square.
Square to camera?
Yeah.
Sure.
Wow.
Ready?
That's good. Yeah, go.
It works.
Yes!
This is amazing!
Go again.
Matt.
Yes?
Have you seen this?
Do it again! Do it again!
Owen, look, look.
Hammer, feather.
Drop!
Galileo was right.
Dude, I just put
a weight in it. What?
"NASA scientist dies."
It's from this morning's paper.
Well, what the...
Matt, it's Lhotsky.
What?
Boles, he must've
known about it.
Listen, think
why Lhotsky's dead.
Obviously, he was talking to
Webb, so they killed him.
They're going to kill me...
We don't know why that guy's dead.
Yes, we do.
They're going to kill me?
What are you talking about?
They're going to kill us both, they're
going to kill the astronauts.
I'm sure... Anyone who
knows about this.
I'm sure Lhotsky knew too much and so
they got rid of him. Okay? That's it.
Right! Right! That's
what I'm talking about!
He was the mole, okay?
No... no, they're tying
off loose ends!
Yeah, and, so, who else
is gonna die, huh?
They're gonna kill Jim Webb? The
head of NASA? He knows, too!
Maybe. Maybe. You don't
think they would?
No! Okay, put the suit on and get
ready, all right? Shut the fuck up.
There's a glob of something on the...
on the glass. Owen, could you get it?
No, it's right... You didn't get it.
It's right there.
Right, right there.
What... What are you doing?
It's just a test.
Boles, I don't take
orders from you!
- Oh, really?
- Enough, come on.
Yeah, I don't take orders from someone
who's trying to get us killed.
Owen, Owen, Owen. Drop it.
He let them get away.
No, he didn't...
Right?
He let them get away!
That's what you did.
Oh, really?
- Yes, you missed on purpose!
- Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa!
What... what are you doing? What
are you doing? We're friends.
Who are they?
We're friends.
Is it Brackett? The CIA?
Why don't you tell him about how you've
been calling Brackett every day,
trying to get Johnson thrown off
the mission. Tell him that!
What are you talking about?
Hey, ask your friend.
Okay, hold on.
Tell him. Tell him.
We choose to go to the moon.
We choose to go to the moon
in this decade
and do the other things.
Not because they are easy,
but because they are hard.
Because that goal will serve
to organize and measure
the best
of our energies and skills.
Because that challenge is one
that we're willing to accept.
One we are unwilling to postpone, and one
we intend to win, and the others, too.
We shall send to the moon,
240,000 miles away from the
control station in Houston,
a giant rocket,
more than 300 feet tall, the
length of this football field,
made of new metal alloys, some of
which have not yet been invented,
capable of standing
heat and stresses
several times more than
have ever been experienced,
on an untried mission
to an unknown celestial body,
and then return it
safely to earth,
re-entering the atmosphere at speeds
of over 25,000 miles per hour,
and do all this... And do
all this and do it right,
and do it first,
before this decade is out,
then we must be bold.
And therefore, as we set sail,
we ask god's blessing on the
most hazardous and dangerous
and greatest adventure on
which man has ever embarked.
Thank you.
So this is the only copy?
Yeah. So, now what? We
just bring it to Brackett?
Oh, I'll take it to Brackett.
You stay here and clean up.
Clean up what?
Clean up the studio.
Destroy everything.
What if we... What if
we need that stuff?
We won't.
Good work.
Thanks.
I'll see you soon.
- Hey, boles.
- Lhotsky wasn't the mole, was he?
What are you talking about?
Yeah, I don't...
I don't know.
I've been working on this too long.
I'm sorry.
Well, get some rest.
I'll see you soon.
Bye, buddy.
He's gonna spot one of our guys pretending
to be a rocket scientist instantly.
We need to send people who are gonna look
like they have no idea what's going on.
They can't make it to the moon.
I'm gonna tell you
what they said.
An ethical problem
with this at all?
He let them get away! That's what you did.
Oh, really?
Yes, you missed on purpose!
Hey whoa, whoa, whoa!
What... what are you doing?
What are you doing?
We're friends!
- Who are they?
- We're friends.
What, you think that's your friend?
Who, Brackett?
The CIA? Why don't you
tell him about how...
Hey, Julie.
Can I borrow your husband?
He what?
Simon's asleep. Inside.
I can go inside
so you guys can talk.
You can stay outside.
No, I don't need to talk.
I wanna know if, um...
If you wanna... we're... We're going
to get rid of the stuff from work.
You can go if you want.
No, I'm going to stay here.
How's Simon? Are you guys
excited about the big launch?
Okay.
Have a good afternoon.
Thanks. You, too.
I'll see you soon, okay?
Yeah, bye.
Good morning.
It's t-minus one hour, 29 minutes
and 53 seconds and counting.
In just an hour and a half, if all
goes well, Apollo eleven astronauts,
Armstrong, Aldrin and Collins
are to lift off
from pad 39-a out there
on the voyage man always
has dreamed about.
Next stop for them, the moon.
And we are all about
to witness the fulfillment
of that promise
that president Kennedy made
at rice university stadium in
Texas, on September 12, 1962.
We passed 10,000 odd cars
parked around the gate-1 area at 4:00 A.M.
when we got here.
Cars from every state, with
little kids staring wide-eyed,
and we saw
teenagers with telescopes.
It was a very moving scene
for me, because
Americans cared then,
I think, and they care now.
And it says, "good luck, Apollo
11" engraved in the sand.
All going very smoothly
here with the count.
T-minus 60 seconds
and counting.
We've passed t-minus 60.
Power transfer is complete.
Twelve, eleven, ten, nine...
Ignition sequence starts.
Six, five, four,
three, two, one.
And good afternoon from ABC
space headquarters in New York.
With me is our science editor, Jules
Bergman and we are on the air today
to bring you a complete report on
some very, very important maneuvers
to be performed by Apollo 11.
Basically a position
to begin the process...
Hello?
Matt?
Are you... Are you
seeing this right now?
- Matt, they're not dead.
- The CIA lied to us.
Wait, what?
The men following us at the
studio are outside my house.
Are you sure? Yes,
meet me at your motel.
What the hell?
Owen?
Hello?
Who's there?
Oh, shit.
Okay, okay, okay.
Uh... uh...
Where's the other car?
Where's the...
Um, um, out back.
Out back.
Okay, stand back.
Sorry.
There is a delirium
of enthusiasm today...
Come on.
Come on, come on.
Come on, Owen.
Come on!
Matt!
What?
There's a car!
Jared, run!
Shit.
Go, go, go.
Andy, hold on.
Fuck.
They're right behind us.
Get their faces! Get their faces, Andy!
Get their faces!
This is fucking crazy!
Oh, god!
Oh, Christ!
He's got a gun!
What?
- He's got a fucking gun.
- Okay, duck, duck, duck!
Shit.
What's happening?
Oh, fuck. Fuck!
Okay, okay.
Get out of here.
I'm trying.
Dude, they're
right in front of us.
Yeah, I know.
They're gonna ram us,
they're gonna ram us!
Oh!
Owen!
So they're not
all labeled, right?
It goes '67, '68, '69. But not
everything's... Not everything's marked.
Well, you'll figure it out.
Hey.
Okay, man.
As soon as I know where
we're going, I'll call you.
Yeah.
Good evening.
Hello, there's a man at the end
of the bar wearing glasses.
Could you please give
the phone to him?
Telephone.
Hello?
You're a real piece of
shit, you know that?
We're looking for you.
Where you been?
Yeah, I'll tell you what,
let's make a trade.
Okay.
My location for the names of
the agents on your kill team.
We don't have any kill team.
Yeah, well, who killed Owen
and hung him in his garage?
Okay. Come down to the office.
We'll discuss it.
Yeah, I'll come in.
No, I'll tell you
what's gonna happen.
I have a film
of everything we did.
I have proof that the CIA conspired
to fake the moon landing
and that Owen Williams is the one that
everybody is about to see walk on the moon.
And that you killed him
to keep it a secret.
I even got you
planning Northwoods,
the same as I got you right now.
No one will take
that seriously, kid.
Yeah, well, call my bluff.
My last movie's about to convince
the world we went to the moon.
Then why don't
I make you a deal?
Come back and work for us,
and I'll make you the head
of your own department.
Yeah, how stupid
do you think I am?
I'll tell you what.
Keep the film as collateral if you
don't believe me. Just think about it.
The surface appears to be, uh,
very, very fine grained as
you get close to it.
It's almost like a powder.
Down there, uh, is very fine.
Okay, I'm going to
step off the LM now.
That's one small step for man,
one giant leap for mankind.
And the, uh, the surface
is fine and powdery.
I can... I can pick
it up loosely with my toe.
It does adhere in fine...
Okay, we shouldn't take
any more pictures on this roll
until earth comes, I don't think.
This is about out, it's just about
out until our last color roll,
so, uh, we'll switch to black and
white as soon as we get to earth.
- We might make it in time.
- Yeah.
There it is, it's coming up.
What?
The earth.
You see it?
Yeah.
Beautiful.
It's half-way up.