My husband used to tell me
I have an overactive
imagination.
I can't help it.
I mean, haven't you ever been
on a train and wondered
about the lives
of the people
who live near the tracks?
The lives you've never lived.
These are things I want to know.
Twice a day, I sit in
the third car from the front
where I have the perfect view
into my favorite house.
Number 15 Beckett road.
I don't know when exactly.
I suppose I started
noticing her about a year ago,
and gradually,
as the months went past,
she became important to me.
I'm not the girl I used to be.
I think people can see it
on my face.
She's what I lost.
She's everything I want to be.
I imagine she's a painter.
She's creative.
He's a doctor or an architect.
He has a good laugh.
She can't cook.
I wonder what they say
to each other
before they go to sleep.
Today her name is Jess;
Tomorrow it could be...
Lisa or Amber.
It all depends on the day;
It depends on my mood.
The truth is,
I don't know her name.
I don't know if she paints or
whether he has a good laugh.
I just know they know love.
Sometimes I catch myself
trying to remember
the last time I had meaningful
contact with another person.
I used to live two doors down,
number 13 Beckett road.
- No.
- It was my first home.
We bought it together.
- It was ours.
- You didn't even like having him over.
I hated it.
Every day,
I tell myself not to look.
But then I look.
Are you alone?
Yeah.
No, it's...
Come. It's all yours.
- Okay.
- Your baby's so cute.
- Oh, thank you.
- Hi, baby!
Is it a... is it a boy?
Yeah!
So sweet.
How ol... how old is he?
- Six months.
So sweet.
Shh.
Here.
A teacher once told me I was
a mistress
of self-reinvention.
Down the center line,
open, around and together...
I wasn't really sure
what it meant at the time.
Around and up.
But since moving here,
I've come to understand it.
Ardsley-on-Hudson
is boring and routine.
It's a fucking baby factory.
I want to start my life
over again.
So far, I've been
a rebellious teenager...
lover...
Waitress...
Gallery director...
Nanny...
and...
A whore.
And not necessarily
in that order.
I can't just be a wife anymore.
That's why I...
Stay awake at night
staring at the ceiling.
In fact, the only time
I feel like myself
is when I'm running.
You always felt that way?
Maybe since I was...
- About 17.
- Mm-hmm.
With Mac.
Mac? Who's Mac?
My brother's best friend.
My brother who died.
I tend to smile
when I'm nervous.
Sometimes I laugh.
For a year, Mac and I lived
in this hunting cabin.
We started fucking.
We were the saddest people
we knew.
But in a way,
that cabin made us happy.
No one could find us.
Everyone thought we were dead.
And if you were
to run away today,
right now, where would you go?
I read once that
when a train hits,
it can rip the clothes
right off of you.
I'm pretty sure Scott thinks
the nanny job is gonna
make me less restless.
Make me want to get pregnant.
And that's not the case?
When I finish work every night,
I run home
and I get in the shower
and I wash the smell
of that baby off of me
as fast as I can.
Ah.
When you woke up this morning,
I went and I brought you
back to bed with me.
And when I was feeding you,
we heard daddy singing
from the kitchen, didn't we?
Aw, daddy came upstairs
with a beautiful breakfast
that he made for mommy,
didn't he?
Yes, he did.
Thank you, Megan.
Oh.
Whew... ah...
- There.
- There you go.
Come here.
- Shh, shh, shh, shh.
- Oh.
Oh, hello.
I swear, I sometimes feel like
my heart is gonna explode.
I mean, look at her.
Look at her.
You're not sleeping.
- Hello?
- You're not sleeping.
Hello?
- Is that another hang-up?
- Mm-hmm.
And grab the corners.
Mm.
And straight.
I got another job.
You what?
I'm really sorry, Anna.
I thought you were happy here.
I mean, you seemed happy here.
I am.
It's just, this isn't what I do.
Take care of children?
Or laundry.
Another gallery headhunted me.
That's great.
The thing is,
it starts tomorrow.
I'm out all day tomorrow.
- That is so uncool.
- I hate to leave you like this
without child care, but...
You don't have a job.
Okay, that sounded wrong.
I know that
you're busy volunteering.
It's not the volunteering.
It's all the shopping,
it's spending hours
in the farmers' market...
It's finding
the right foods for her,
it's pureeing sweet potatoes,
and I do all of this
at the same time...
As I'm nursing.
Maybe you should go
back to work, too.
Mothers need to work.
It's actually better
for the kid.
And how would you know?
Your key.
There's no job more important
than raising a child.
Megan, please. I...
Rachel.
What are you doing?
Give me my baby.
Rachel, what are you doing?
Hello?
Oh.
- Thank you.
- Here.
Mm. Beautiful.
How many times
has she texted you today?
I don't know.
She called the landline
three times.
Oh.
- You have to talk to her.
- I know. I-I...
It's getting crazy.
I will. I know, I know, I know.
- Okay.
- It's gonna be fine.
Isn't it always fine?
Don't I always make
everything fine?
Stop.
Who gives a shit?
It's your birthday.
Are you sure you don't want me
to take you out tonight?
- No, I like it at home.
- Call Megan.
Ask her to come back.
She just quit.
She what?
She just told me
she got another job.
Oh.
Shame. Thought you guys were
kind of a good team together.
Mm.
So did I.
Hey, it's tom.
Sorry I missed you.
I'll get right back to you.
Hey, tom.
It's me.
Uh, I just wanted
to wish mama a happy birthday.
- Happy birthday, mama.
- Rachel.
Jesus.
No, no, no, no, no.
No, don't, Cathy.
Please stop it.
- Relax. Relax!
- Cathy, come on!
I just... I just need some
to go to sleep.
That's all.
I just need... I just...
I just need a little bit
to go to sleep.
What brought this on?
He posted another picture
of the baby.
- It was a cute picture.
- Yeah?
Yup.
Facebook and drunk ex-wives
do not make good friends.
I got it. I got it.
All right.
Let's get you to your room.
Rachel, you have to stop
calling them, okay?
I really appreciate this room.
I do.
I thought that
I would just be here for...
For a couple of weeks or months.
Yeah, that was two years ago.
Get some sleep.
I've rarely works
the first time.
Would you like a moment?
It's okay, sweetie.
We're gonna try again.
We can't afford to do it again.
Well, when we can, we will.
I wonder what she's looking at.
Or if she even sees
this train at all.
Who is that man?
The next station is
Ardsley-on-Hudson.
What is she doing?
She's throwing it all away.
Anna, I fell asleep last night
thinking of you.
I dreamed about kissing
the inside of your thighs
and holding your breasts.
God, I wish
I was fucking you right now.
Anna, I love you.
I love you so much.
When it happened to me,
I found dozens of e-mails.
Tom told her that he never
felt like this before.
He said it wouldn't be
that much longer
until they were together.
I know what they say,
and you shouldn't
check his e-mail.
It was stupid.
But when I, um...
When I saw
it was from the realtor,
I thought that it was just spam.
And then I realized that
they were kisses, not X's,
and my husband was fucking
a century 21 agent.
That sucks.
It does.
Her name was Anna Boyd,
and he was in love with her.
Come here for one second.
Say, "fuck you, Anna Boyd,"
but just yell it, all right?
Fuck you, Anna Boyd!
That bitch is living
in my house.
I picked everything
in that house.
I picked everything.
I picked the dining table,
the kitchen table.
I wonder if she knows
that I fucked tom
on the same table
that her baby eats at.
I just want to tell her.
Oh, I wish I could tell her.
I picked everything
in that house.
I fucking picked
everything in that house.
I...
I could never find the words
to describe how I felt
when I read that e-mail.
But this morning, I did.
I did.
When I saw that woman...
Kissing someone else, just...
I... betraying her husband,
I felt... I felt it.
I felt pure rage.
It was like something
had been taken from me again,
and... just thought
if I could...
If I could,
I'd just go to her house
and I'd go and...
Find her sitting
at the kitchen table,
and I'd just...
I'd wrap my hand
in her long blond hair,
and I'd jerk her head back.
I'd just jerk it back.
And then I'd pull it down
to the ground,
and I would just...
Smash her head
all over the floor!
Move! Get out of my way!
Move! Move.
Hey!
You whore!
Jesus Christ, Rachel.
Uh, what the hell
is wrong with you?
I spent the past hour
driving around looking for you.
You... you scared
the shit out of Anna.
Do you know that?
She thought you were gonna...
She-she wanted to call
the police, so just...
Leave us alone.
You can ruin your own life
if you want to,
but you're not
gonna destroy ours.
I'm not gonna
protect you anymore.
Oh, my god.
God.
Rachel?
Open the door.
Cathy, I just...
I just need a sec.
Are you okay?
Rachel, open the door.
I have a stomach flu.
- Okay? I just...
- You don't have a flu.
What the fuck, Rachel?
I'm not stupid!
Rachel!
Cathy, just go away!
Come here for one second.
Just one second.
Say, "fuck you, Anna Boyd."
- Fuck you, Anna Boyd!
You whore!
No!
Anyone counting days one to 90,
who would like
to share a day count?
Hey, I'm Jason.
I'm an alcoholic.
- Welcome, Jason.
- I've got 22 days back.
Nice.
- There we go.
- Good job.
Anyone else?
Hi. I'm-I'm Rachel and...
Welcome, Rachel.
- Hi, Rachel.
- And this... thank you.
This is day one, I-I suppose.
Um...
I'm here because I...
because I...
Because I woke up,
um, covered in blood.
And I had... I had bruises
all over my arm and, um...
It's usually from
when I've fallen
and someone's helped me up.
My husband...
He used to tell me
what I'd done the night before.
And I learned,
when you wake up like that,
you just say you're sorry.
You just say you're sorry
for what you did
and you're sorry
for who you are,
and you're never
gonna do it again.
But you do. You do it again.
And there's some time missing.
I need to remember.
Okay.
Thank you, Rachel.
Am I... am I right?
- Or am I nuts?
- No.
Make an effort!
You know, we all worked hard.
That was a charity event.
- You don't wear that.
- No, you don't.
Right? It was that,
um, the homeless thing.
I don't remember
what it was called.
Oh, oh, safe shelter.
Yeah.
That was a tube top, right?
Yup. It was.
I can't.
Why say, "yes, I'm gonna go,
"and I can't wait because
it's fun to dress up."
Then dress up.
Do you like
devil's eggs, Martha?
Deviled eggs? Yeah, I do.
- Deviled egg.
- Thank you for making them.
The classics. Do you want
to try one, anybody?
Uh, those go outside. I don't
want the eggs with the dessert.
It doesn't fucking matter
where they go, okay?
So do you want to put them
here? Do you want them
with your hot dogs
or you can put a couple
with your quinoa if you want to.
Do you want to put them with
your other salad and your corn?
- Rachel.
- Put a couple on the wall?
Rachel.
I'm fine, tom!
- Stop it.
- Come on.
You didn't back me up.
You never have my back.
That's my boss's wife.
Probably got me fired
back there.
I don't give a fuck.
I'm your wife.
- I'm your wife and you never...
- Rachel.
- You never fucking support me.
- Rachel, please stop it.
Hey, come on.
Need you to focus here.
Don't fucking talk
- to me like that!
- Relax!
Relax!
- Rachel.
- Hi, Cathy. I'm sorry.
- There you are.
- I need to get my shit together.
- I'm s...
- Shh.
You must be Ms. Watson.
I'm detective Riley.
This is detective Gaskill.
We need to ask you
a few questions.
What's this about?
Want to sit down?
Can you tell me
where you were Friday night?
I-I was at work
in the city, and then...
and then I went
to visit my husband.
You mean your ex-husband?
Yeah.
So I got off the train
at Ardsley-on-Hudson,
and then...
And then I decided
that it was a bad idea.
Around what time
did you reach that conclusion?
I was back here by 11:00.
Yeah. Yeah.
On your way back here,
did you stop anywhere?
No.
And what time did you
take the train there?
Um, 6:00. I...
So...
What'd you do
during those hours in Ardsley,
if you weren't seeing
your ex-husband?
Do you remember
seeing this woman?
She worked for your ex-husband.
She's gone missing.
What do you mean, she's missing?
Well, her husband said
she never came back home
the same night you got off
the train in Ardsley-on-Hudson.
I was just... I was just...
Do you know Megan Hipwell?
- No!
- Did you see her?
No, I don't...
I don't think so.
Is that because
you were inebriated?
Just to clarify, you said
you were at work Friday?
Are you referring to your job
in public relations?
Right.
It's my understanding
you were fired
from that job over a year ago
because of
your drinking problem.
Okay. That's enough for now.
If you're able
to remember anything else,
give us a call.
Did you really get fired?
Look, I didn't want you to worry
that I couldn't pay the rent.
If you don't have a job,
then what do you do every day?
I...
I-I ride the train.
You what?
I ride the train
to New York and back.
That's what
your alimony's paying for,
just tickets to nowhere?
That's really fucking weird,
Rachel.
O-okay, okay.
I just, I-I got on the train,
and then... and then I...
I got off the train.
I don't know.
It's-it's very unclear.
You don't remember anything,
do you?
You know, I read about this man
in long island...
Who blacked out.
He left a bar,
drove to the house
that he'd grown up in,
stabbed its occupants to death.
He woke up the next morning,
oblivious to what he did
until the police
came to get him.
- Rachel!
- What? What?
You have to leave.
I can't do this anymore.
- I'll give you a few weeks...
- Hold on.
Hold on.
Detective Riley!
- Yeah, I agree with you.
- Detective Riley!
I saw someone
with Megan Hipwell,
but, uh, not on Friday night.
She...
She was having an affair,
she had a lover... that's what
- I'm trying to tell you.
- I thought you didn't know her.
No. But I s... but I saw her.
- You saw her where?
- I-I saw her from the train.
She was standing on-on the deck
with this man.
- With her husband, Scott Hipwell?
- No, it wasn't him.
This... man was different,
and th-they were...
They were kissing.
Wow. That's pretty
coincidental, isn't it?
You just happen to be on a train
at the same exact moment
that a woman you don't know,
but somehow recognize,
is cheating on her husband?
I-I know it sounds crazy.
Um...
Neighbors saw a drunk woman
in the vicinity of her house
Friday night.
Megan Hipwell does bear
a resemblance to Anna Watson.
Mrs. Watson reported
that you go to their house
sometimes uninvited,
and that on one occasion
you actually broke in
and took their child.
Let me give you some advice.
Don't go back to Beckett road.
Don't contact your ex-husband.
Don't go anywhere near
Anna Watson or her baby.
Are you listening to me?
Yes.
You don't live there anymore.
Stay away.
You know, I lie all the time.
I lie to Scott.
I lie to you.
I mean, I know that's not
the point of therapy, but...
I have to keep things vague.
Jumble up all the men
and the exes, the lovers.
It doesn't matter who they are.
It matters
how they make me feel.
Lying is like taking a trip.
It's like having a secret.
It's like touching yourself
and no one else knows.
Except you.
But you're just pretending.
You're just pretending
to touch yourself.
Scott's possessive, jealous.
He likes to own me.
He figures out all my passwords.
Which is kind of sexy.
So, when I came home last night,
Scott was on my laptop,
wondering why...
Scott's behavior is not normal.
It's a form of emotional abuse.
Are you ever afraid of Scott?
It's not abuse.
Not if you don't care,
and I don't.
Maybe it's become
a normal state for you.
Is it normal I think about you
all the time?
"Almost exactly a week ago,
"Megan Hipwell walked out
of number 15 Beckett road
"and disappeared.
"No one has seen her since.
"Neither her phone
nor her bank cards
"have been used since Friday.
"A wonderful woman,
"an intensely private person
with a warm heart.
"She lost a brother
when she was 16,
"and both her parents died
a few years ago.
"Scott Hipwell urges
anyone with information
to please come forward."
You Megan's friend?
Yes. Rachel.
Come in.
- Do you want a coffee?
- Uh, sure. Thank you.
Sorry it's a mess.
I've been hunting for her
social, her birth certificate.
And the cops need a lot.
Have we met somewhere before?
I... I don't think so.
And you know Megan from...?
Uh, from the gallery.
Oh, you're an artist?
Uh, well, I like to think so.
So, you said on the phone
you wanted to tell me
something about Megan.
What did you want to tell me?
I saw your wife...
With someone...
On Friday morning.
With who?
She was up there on your porch.
Um... I saw her from the train,
because I commute
to Manhattan every day
and I go straight past here.
She kissed him.
They were kissing.
I'm sorry.
I know this is
a terrible thing to hear.
Yeah.
I know how it feels.
What did he look like?
He-he was...
He was average height.
He had dark hair.
And they were out there
on the porch?
Yes.
Fuck.
Oh, no, no, no. Thank you.
Okay, sure.
Uh, it could... I-I don't know.
Maybe it's a good thing.
Could mean she's all right.
She just ran off with someone.
Right.
Has she talked to you?
Oh, no, n...
Um, I haven't heard anything.
But you know her well enough
to know where we live.
Megan doesn't have many friends.
Well, I used to live nearby,
and, um, she and I,
we took... we took yog...
We took Pilates... together.
I-I think I should go.
I feel like I've taken up
too much of your time, and...
So sorry
to have had to tell you...
Tell you that in that way and...
Hey.
Do you think you'd recognize
him again if you saw him?
I don't know.
There's a guy. A therapist.
His name's, um, ab...
Abdic... Abdic.
Uh, Kamal... Abdic.
Is that who you saw?
I don't know.
I really can't tell.
She spends a lot of
fucking time with her shrink.
That's him.
I remember. That's him.
I remember.
That's him.
I'm sorry.
Where are you? Where are you?
Where are you?
Stay away from me!
This is so stupid.
He makes every conversation
about getting pregnant.
And every time we go there...
Where?
To that subject.
What subject?
Megan.
It's okay.
No!
Megan.
All right, Megan.
We shouldn't.
No.
Megan.
Don't make it impossible
for us to work together.
Meg...
Megan, I could lose my practice.
I don't give a fuck!
I don't give a fuck
about your fucking practice!
I don't give a...
Dr. Kamal Abdic...
Dr. Kamal Abdic
has been brought in
for questioning
on the disappearance
of Ardsley-on-Hudson resident
Megan Hipwell.
He was, according to sources,
Mrs. Hipwell's psychiatrist.
For the first time in ages,
I have purpose.
Or at least
I have a distraction.
I want Megan to show up
safe and sound.
I do.
Yeah!
Just not quite yet.
Hi.
What's wrong?
Abdic's been released.
- What?
- There wasn't enough evidence.
And because I'm the one that
got him arrested, he talked.
A lot.
They'll... they'll build a case
against him.
It'll just take some time.
Are you totally sure he's
the guy you saw Megan with?
Yes.
You sure as fuck better be.
I don't understand.
- The police think I did it.
- Yeah, but he's...
- He's the one...
- He told them Megan's miserable.
That I'm a jealous,
controlling husband.
I'm sure that they're just...
Trying to rule you out.
Abdic told them I'm abusive.
When she walked out,
I... I didn't go after her.
I never called to check on her.
I went to a sports bar,
for fuck's sake.
Got drunk.
No, we j...
We just need to find
more evidence on Abdic.
I've spent the whole day
going through her stuff.
There's no e-mails.
There's nothing.
No letters, no e-mails.
Nothing.
For a second, I thought about
contacting Abdic myself.
Fucking phone won't stop!
This is Scott.
Yeah, yeah.
H-hold on, hold on.
Do you mind?
Oh. Come here.
Oh, you're heavy. You're heavy.
- You're getting a little fatty.
- Rachel, no.
Anna, get in the house.
Your-your... your wife hit me
on Friday night!
No. What are you talking about?
Yes. Yes, yes, you did.
Yes, you did!
And then sh... and then she...
She-she got in your car.
No. She said you yelled at her
that night.
No, that is not what happened.
She was... she was in
the tunnel, and she-she hit me.
I don't want to argue
in the street.
The middle of the day
and you're drunk.
Look, I'm not drunk, tom.
My wife is scared of you.
Of what?
I don't even know
if that's a joke or not.
- Let's start with child abduction.
- That's bullshit.
You know that's not
how it happened.
You and I both know
what you're capable of.
Were you just
at Scott Hipwell's house?
Why are you at
Scott Hipwell's house?
Because I'm helping...
I'm helping him.
- How?
- To try and find Megan.
You don't even know Megan.
Rach...
I don't think
you're helping anybody.
So you're here because you want
to uncover lost memories.
- Is that correct?
- You have an accent.
Pardon?
No, sorry, I-I, um,
wasn't expecting you
to have an accent.
Well, you have an accent.
Where are you from?
I'm an American citizen.
But I guess you're not here
to talk about me.
- Unless you are.
- No, no, I...
Sorry, I was just, uh, just
trying to make conversation.
The blackouts.
You're experiencing blackouts?
Mm-hmm.
Do you want to tell me
about them?
Mm...
Well, when I...
Wake up, and when someone
tells me what I've done...
it just doesn't feel like me
or like something
that I would do.
I feel bad about it, but, um...
But it's like
it's so far removed,
that I have a...
I just don't feel bad enough.
And you want to take
personal responsibility
for what you've done,
but you find it difficult
to feel accountable because
you can't even remember it.
Yeah?
Yeah.
So, Rachel, besides drinking...
Because you clearly drink.
You've been drinking today,
haven't you?
What else do you enjoy?
Do you have any hobbies?
I like to draw. Art.
I guess.
Good. We can try to...
Regain some of your memories
by drawing them.
I've tried it. It doesn't work.
And have you ever tracked
all the way back
to when you started
drinking heavily?
When was that?
It was with tom.
When I couldn't get pregnant.
Who's tom?
He's my ex-husband.
You want to talk about that?
I really wanted a baby.
And we tried everything,
and nothing worked.
And it just absolutely...
It just broke my...
My heart, and...
So it got really sad.
And then, um...
and then the-the booze
just, uh, broke us.
Good.
Tell me more.
I used to watch
this perfect couple.
And they were just the...
Embodiment of...
True love.
It's like the kind of love
you always want.
And then she betrayed him.
And it sparked something in me.
Why are you really here, Rachel?
Because I'm afraid of myself.
July 5th.
1:33 and 1:34.
1:37.
She calls again 1:38.
And then she calls again
at 1:44, 1:45,
2:15 P.M.
And July 6th.
You get the point.
She sometimes texted him
dozens of times a day.
But these are all
from an unknown number.
- Mm, and unknown is Rachel.
- You have a log
of the calls;
You don't have a log
of what they're saying
to each other.
Look, um...
Has she been back to the house
- since the incident with your child?
- Not that I know of.
Well, then you may have a case
for harassment
in the second degree,
but these are texts,
they're not threats, so...
She has been hanging around
Scott Hipwell's house.
A lot.
Yeah, I'm aware.
There are a lot
of loose ends here
that suggest something,
but they don't add up to much.
If you could bring me
something more solid...
What more do you need?
Evidence.
Real evidence.
You sure your husband
doesn't want to stay in touch
with his ex-wife?
What? No.
She's harassing us.
Is that what he calls it?
Hi.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Hi.
Reporters are in my yard.
They're everywhere.
I didn't know where else to go.
Come in.
The detective just...
The detective
just told me something
I've wanted to hear
for a long time.
She's pregnant.
She told her shrink but not me.
I wanted a family.
But she fought me
every step of the way.
We always fought about it.
Did Megan ever say anything
about me to you?
She loved you.
She loved you in ways
that people only dream
of being loved.
You shouldn't be here.
I just...
I need to tell someone.
Just once.
Just say it out loud.
I want to tell you.
And then I'll be gone.
I swear.
I got pregnant.
I was 17.
I had her by myself.
She had dark eyes
and blond hair.
I expected it to be hard,
but it wasn't.
It was easy.
Because I loved her.
I loved her.
We called her Elizabeth.
Libby.
It was December.
We had gotten in a fight,
me and Mac.
He'd gone off
and... and left.
The roof was leaking.
It was freezing cold, so...
I got in the tub.
I brought Libby in with me.
Put her on my chest.
Her head just... under my chin.
I fell asleep.
I let her go.
I...
I couldn't look.
I didn't want to see it.
I wrapped her in a blanket,
and I buried her.
And...
Mac went out that night...
and he never came back.
He never came back.
I missed our home.
So one day, when I was drunk,
I decided to go there.
The front door was open;
It's not like I broke in.
And then I heard Evie.
Who's Evie?
Tom's baby.
And I know this sounds...
Insane...
But I just wanted to hold her.
Just for a moment.
Rachel.
What are you doing?
Rachel...
Give her to me.
Shh, shh, shh.
Oh. Mommy's here.
Shh.
Oh.
I wasn't going to hurt her.
I would never hurt her.
I just wanted to hold her.
"Partially decomposed
body found.
"Female body found. Death a
result of blunt force trauma.
"Blunt force trauma, partially
decomposed body found...
"Megan Hipwell,
blunt force trauma,
"partially decomposed...
"The investigation now
being called a homicide.
"Sources say the partially
decomposed body found
"is missing Ardsley woman
Megan Hipwell.
"Death a result
of blunt force trauma.
Megan Hipwell's investigation
now being called a homicide."
Mr. Hipwell!
What's wrong?
I'm sorry.
This reminds me of when I used
to watch you getting dressed
before going back to her.
Back to this house.
I actually miss being
the other woman.
Did you enjoy
cheating on Rachel?
Seriously?
Can we not fixate on her?
I saw her again today.
Where?
This afternoon, when the police
brought Scott back home.
She was across the street.
And when she saw me,
she got aggressive.
Aggressive how?
What if Rachel killed Megan?
Rachel did not kill Megan.
Then why is she creeping
around Scott's house?
- She's dangerous, and you know it.
- Anna, Anna.
Sweetheart...
Rachel is a sad person.
She's completely harmless.
What are you doing here?
How di... how did you get in?
Come here.
Have a beer with me.
Uh, I'm-I'm not drinking
right now.
Detective Riley
came to see me last night.
It turns out,
I'm not the father.
Neither is the shrink.
Did my wife confide in you
about a third man?
Sit down.
Sit down!
Look, I don't know, I don't
know what this is about...
Oh, come on.
You and Megan
were such good friends.
You must've known.
Admit it.
Admit what?
Admit that you never even
fucking met my wife.
The detective said
you didn't even know Megan.
She used other words, too.
Alcoholic.
Maybe even mentally unstable.
I am sorry.
I was honestly just
trying to help you.
You're tom's crazy ex.
When the fuck were you
gonna tell me that, huh?
And now the detective
is asking if you and I are
in a relationship?
You?
I would never even
get near someone like you!
My wife is dead.
And you're lying to me!
What's wrong with you?
- Who does this?
- I needed to tell you
about Megan's affair,
and you wouldn't
have believed me
if I was just tom's ex!
Oh, well, thank you, you know?
For getting Abdic
to point the finger at me.
For getting the cops to say
that you and I are fucking!
How are they going, huh?
You know, the sessions.
With the doctor.
I wanted to know about Abdic.
And I-I went to him
to help you...
You're just a sad liar
with no life.
- You're all liars.
- Please...
I need to file a statement.
Name.
Rachel Watson.
Pete, I got this.
You wanted to file a statement?
I'm listening.
Scott Hipwell just assaulted me.
You mean your new boyfriend,
Scott Hipwell?
No, we-we were just friends.
But that's what you wanted,
isn't it?
I mean, you got him
to stay overnight
- at your apartment, right?
- No, you-you...
You need the context...
I know the context, but
what I'm trying to determine
is when your obsession
with Mr. Hipwell began.
Was it before or after
his pregnant wife was murdered?
I mean, you were neighbors
at one point.
I met him after.
After being questioned by me,
you befriend another even more
obvious suspect than yourself,
and then you manage to get him
to incriminate himself,
all the while
hoping he'll fuck you.
I came here trying to help you!
He just assaulted me
in my own house!
You were seen
in the area that night.
There are several hours
that you say
you can't account for.
It was Scott.
Scott Hipwell killed his wife.
No, he didn't.
Surveillance footage
from a sports bar
accounts for Mr. Hipwell's
whereabouts that night.
You're lying. You're lying.
Tell me what happened.
It's okay.
Tell me.
I don't know.
Did you murder Megan Hipwell?
Hi.
I need to see you.
Can you please come over?
I can still see her dark eyes.
I can smell her skin.
I can feel how cold she was.
Forgive yourself.
You don't have to be afraid
of being alone.
You're not alone.
The next
station is Ardsley-on-Hudson.
You'll be fine.
You and your baby will be fine.
Why are you following me?
Why are you here?
Uh...
I could ask you
the same question.
I saw you.
I saw you that night
in the tunnel.
I saw you there.
- And I-I know I saw you there.
- All right.
Lady, I live here.
I'm always in that tunnel.
But-but what did you,
what did you see?
What happened that night?
What did you see?
All right, you, uh...
You busted your ass.
You fell.
I felt sorry for you.
I tried to help you up.
You told me to fuck off,
so I fucked off.
Was I with anyone?
Was I, was I alone?
Was i... what happened?
I don't know.
You were wasted.
You're always wasted.
That's all I can tell you.
Whoa, take it easy.
I need you to tell me
the fucking truth.
What did you see that night?
What happened that night?
Uh... I don't know.
I'm assuming it's the worst.
God.
Come here for one second.
Just one second.
Say, "fuck you, Anna Boyd."
- Fuck you, Anna Boyd!
I wonder if she knows
that I fucked tom on the...
When I saw that woman
kissing someone else,
betraying her husband,
I felt it.
Pure rage.
If I could, I'd go to her house,
I'd find her sitting and...
I'd smash her head
all over the floor!
Cathy,
thank you for all
you have done for me.
I'm sorry to leave this way.
I'll send for my things later.
Love, Rachel.
That's so true.
It's the worst restaurant ever.
Why do we keep going back?
Martha.
Rachel?
Wow, I haven't seen you
in a million years.
Um...
Yeah, I-I wanted to call you,
um, but tom said I should
just leave it alone.
- Oh.
- Um...
I'm so sorry.
For what?
For the barbecue.
And I just need you to know
that I-I don't remember
anything and, um,
I just completely blacked out.
Everyone had a little
too much to drink,
- so it's okay.
- I know, but, uh,
with the eggs
and then I-I screamed at you.
That I was that abusive,
I just feel...
I just feel so ashamed about it.
Um...
I don't...
Tom... tom said that, um...
That I smashed your plate.
I don't...
Tom was fired...
Fired because of how I behaved.
You felt sick and you took
a nap in our guest bedroom.
You want to lie down?
- Come with me.
- Okay.
Excuse us.
Rachel, are you feeling better?
You guys can
stay tonight if you want.
- No, no. That's fine, thanks.
- Okay.
I think I'd remember
if you caused a scene.
I'm so sorry.
Get up.
And then tom took you home.
- Sorry, tom...
- Stop fucking saying that!
- I know you're sorry!
- Sorry.
What's your fucking problem?
Can't even focus on me.
Can't even fucking stand up!
What is wrong with you?
Can you stand?
Fucking disgusting.
N-no.
No.
Yeah, tom got fired
'cause he couldn't keep
his dick in his pants.
You did nothing wrong.
Nothing.
Wake the fuck up, Rachel.
Wake the fuck up!
Wake up!
You can sleep out here.
We all felt so bad for you.
He's such a bad guy.
Oh, god.
Are you okay?
Hmm.
I need to see you.
Meet me at 3:00.
I'm here. Where are you?
I can't.
I'm stuck watching Evie.
What are you doing up?
Picking up after Evie.
You whore!
Leave us alone.
No new messages.
No saved messages.
To hear your current
voice mail greeting,
please press two.
Hi, it's Megan.
Leave a message.
To replay this greeting,
press one.
Hi, it's Megan.
Leave a message.
You okay?
I thought I heard something.
You should wake me up
if you heard something.
I just, I...
Well, come back to bed.
Whore!
Rachel's down there.
What the hell are you doing?
Come here.
Hey, get the fuck
out of here, okay?
Get the fuck out of here!
You're okay.
Just need some help.
Don't touch me.
Just need to get
a little help up.
- Just fuck off. Fuck off!
- Come on. Come on.
You're heavy. Aw.
Come here.
Anna?
No.
- Anna, please, please?
- No, go away.
- There's... okay.
- Go!
I'm-I'm gonna stand right here.
I'm not gonna come closer.
I just need to talk to you.
I don't want to hear
anything you have to say.
Where's tom?
He's lying to you.
He-he always does.
He's-he's a good liar...
I know he's a good liar.
We went behind your back
for months.
He's just done it to you.
I know he's cheating.
I know.
Anna, he-he killed Megan...
No, we don't,
we don't know that.
- He's dangerous.
- We don't know anything.
- Anna, you-you need to leave.
- No. No.
You need to leave.
You need to take Evie
- and you need to leave, get out of here.
- No.
- It's not safe...
- I'm not leaving him.
It's hardly the first time
he's had an affair.
It's not about the affair.
And you... you know that
deep down.
Anna, please,
- just come with me.
- I'm not leaving him.
Please come with me.
- Anna, don't, don't...
- Come in the house, honey.
Please.
I saw you, tom.
You motherfucker!
I saw you, you murderer!
You fucking murderer!
You killed her!
You fucking killed her!
I know it!
Un-fucking-believable!
Now, listen. Listen to me.
Megan got into his car
that night.
You think I don't remember.
You thought I blacked out!
I saw you.
Why did Megan get in your car?
- Did Megan get in your car?
- No!
Yes, she did.
Tell her the truth.
Just tell her
the truth right now.
You attacked me in that tunnel
because I saw her with you.
I found Megan's phone.
I found it.
So, all those phone calls,
they weren't from Rachel.
So, were you fucking her
while she was here working?
While she was looking after
our daughter?
You... you were
so tired all the time.
It's all about Evie.
That's right.
Your daddy loves you.
Tom?
- Give her to me.
- That's right.
Your daddy loves you.
Tom, give her to me, please?
- Please give her to me.
- It's fine.
I think she needs
changing, please.
No, she's gonna be fine.
Please just give her to me.
Oh, okay. Shh, shh.
- Let her go. You're going to hurt her.
- Change her here.
- You're... okay.
I'll change her. Let her go.
You're gonna hurt her.
Shh.
You're okay, you're okay.
Shh, shh.
Shh.
911, what's your...
What's your emergency?
No, no. Stay.
Stay.
Do you need a drink?
No.
Yeah, you do.
All those things
that you said I did.
Those terrible things...
I didn't do any of them.
You just watched me suffer.
You made me feel so worthless.
You made me think that
everything was my fault.
Drink it.
You told me I got you fired.
But I didn't.
You know, I saw Martha
on the train...
Drink it!
I saw Martha on the train.
And she told me
that you were fired
because you were fucking
everyone in the office!
Rachel's down there.
Wait here.
You gonna get in the car?
What's going on?
Don't worry about it.
Come on.
Okay, I'm here.
So, what is it?
I just want to go to the woods.
What is it with you crazy women?
This what you want?
No.
Like this?
What?
I'm pregnant.
Congratulations.
I thought you should know.
You thought I should know?
There's a chance
it could be yours.
Then get an abortion.
Or if it's Scott's,
do whatever you want.
But if it's not,
then get rid of it.
You can be as involved
as you want.
You were a shitty nanny.
What makes you think
you're gonna be a good mother?
Why did you bring me there
in the first place?
Because I thought it would be
fun to have you both around.
Come on.
I played your game
so you could fuck me
in between Evie's playdates.
I don't need another kid.
Certainly not with you.
I took care of your kid
to be near you!
You fucked Anna 'cause you
couldn't fuck Rachel anymore,
and you fucked me 'cause
you couldn't fuck Anna!
Take us all away
and you're just a pathetic,
impotent man!
You're... you're not
gonna get rid of me.
You're gonna pay for this child
for the rest of your life.
I can just... yeah.
You're like a dog.
Like one of those unwanted,
mistreated dogs.
And you can kick them.
They keep coming back to you.
Thinking that somehow
if they're good...
You're not doing this again.
You'll love them.
This is what you do.
You're not doing this to me.
You brought this
on yourself, Rachel.
If you had just stayed away
that one night...
Just left us all alone.
You brought this on Megan.
In a way, you killed her.
Mm-hmm.
But I didn't.
You did.
No!
No...
You did this to me
in our marriage.
You made me fucking crazy.
Do you have any idea
what it's like to be
married to a fucking blur?
I had no choice. He was...
He would've killed me.
I never wanted to hurt him.
It was self-defense.
She had no choice.
Tom would've killed her.
I saw the whole thing.
Rachel was right about Megan.
She was right about everything.
We are tied forever now,
the three of us.
Bound forever
by the story we share.
Today I sit in a different car.
And I look ahead.
Anything is possible,
because I am not the girl
I used to be.
Psagmeno.com
MOViE iNFO WiTH.srt FiLES!